I can't let you out, Hedwig.
내보내 줄 수 없어
헤드위그
I'm not allowed to use
magic outside of school.
학교 밖에서 마술을 쓰면
안 된단 말이야
- Besides, if Uncle Vernon...
- Harry Potter!
- 게다가 버논 삼촌이…
- 해리 포터!
Now you've done it.
이제 큰일 났다
He's in there. Vernon?
저기 계신다, 버논?
I'm warning you, if you can't control
that bloody bird, it'll have to go.
경고하는데, 그 망할 새
제대로 간수 못 할 거면 버려
But she's bored.
지루해서 저래요
If I could only let her
out for an hour or two.
한두 시간만 풀어 줄게요
So you can send secret messages to
your freaky little friends? No, sir.
괴짜 친구들한테 비밀 메시지를
보내려고? 어림없는 소리
But I haven't had any messages
from any of my friends.
하지만 친구들한테서
아무 편지도 못 받았어요
Not one...
하나도요
...all summer.
여름 내내 말이죠
Who would want to be
friends with you?
누가 너랑 친구가
되고 싶겠어?
I should think you'd be
a little more grateful.
좀 감사할 줄 알아라
We've raised you since you were a baby,
given you the food off our table...
우린 널 아기 때부터 키우며
밥을 먹여 줬고
...even let you have
Dudley's second bedroom...
두들리의 두 번째
침실까지 내줬다고
...purely out of the
goodness of our hearts.
단지 우리의
선량함 때문에 말이야
Not now. It's for when
the Masons arrive.
- 메이슨 부부가 올 때까지 기다리렴
- 금방 오실 거다
Which should be any minute.
Now, let's go over our
schedule once again, shall we?
스케줄을 다시 한 번
검토해 보지
Petunia, when the Masons
arrive, you will be...?
여보, 손님들이
도착하면 당신은…
In the lounge, waiting to welcome
them graciously to our home.
거실에서 그분들을
환영할 준비를 해야죠
- Good. And, Dudley, you will be...?
- I'll be waiting to open the door.
- 좋아, 두들리는?
- 전 문을 열어 드려요
Excellent.
좋았어
And you?
그럼 넌?
I'll be in my bedroom, making no noise
and pretending that I don't exist.
제 침실에서
쥐 죽은 듯이 있어야죠
Too right, you will.
바로 그거다
With any luck, this could be the day I
make the biggest deal of my career...
운이 좋다면 오늘 내 평생
가장 큰 거래가 성사될 텐데
...and you will not mess it up.
네가 망쳐서는 안 되지
Harry Potter, such
an honor it is.
해리 포터!
정말 영광입니다
- Who are you? - Dobby,
sir. Dobby the house-elf.
- 넌 누구지?
- 전 도비예요, 집요정이죠
Not to be rude or anything...
미안하지만
...but this isn't a great time for me
to have a house-elf in my bedroom.
지금은 내 방에 요정을
들여놓을 때가 아니야
Yes, sir. Dobby understands.
네, 도비는 이해해요
It's just that Dobby has
come to tell you...
도비는 그냥
말씀드리러 온 건데…
It is difficult, sir. Dobby
wonders where to begin.
어렵군요, 어떻게 말을
꺼내야 할지 모르겠어요
- Why don't you sit down?
- Sit down? Sit down?
- 우선 좀 앉지그래?
- 앉으라고요? 앉으라고요?
Dobby, I'm sorry. I didn't mean
to offend you or anything.
도비, 미안해
화나게 할 뜻은 없었어
Offend Dobby?
도비를 화나게 한다고요?
Dobby has heard of
your greatness, sir...
해리 포터가
위대하다는 소리는 들었지만
...but never has he been asked to sit
down by a wizard, like an equal.
마법사에게 동등한 존재처럼
앉으라는 말을 듣긴 처음이에요
You can't have met many
decent wizards then.
좋은 마법사들을
많이 못 만났나 보구나
No, I haven't.
네, 맞아요
That was an awful thing to say.
그런 나쁜 말을 하면
안 되는데
- Bad Dobby! Bad Dobby!
- Stop, Dobby. Dobby, shush.
- 나쁜 도비! 나쁜 도비!
- 멈춰, 도비, 조용!
Dobby, please, stop.
도비, 제발 그만해
Don't mind that.
It's just the cat.
상관 마세요, 고양이랍니다
- Bad Dobby. - Stop! Stop,
Dobby. Please, be quiet.
- 나쁜 도비!
- 제발, 도비! 조용히 좀 해
Are you all right?
괜찮아?
Dobby had to punish
himself, sir.
도비는 자신에게
벌을 줘야 했어요
Dobby almost spoke ill
of his family, sir.
도비는 자기 가족을
욕할 뻔했어요
- Your family? - The wizard
family Dobby serves, sir.
- 가족?
- 도비가 모시는 마법사 가족요
Dobby is bound to serve
one family forever.
도비는 평생 한 가족만
모시게 되어 있어요
If they ever knew
Dobby was here...
그들이 도비가
여기 왔다는 걸 알면…
But Dobby had to come. Dobby has to
protect Harry Potter. To warn him.
하지만 도비는 해리 포터를 보호하고
경고하러 와야 했어요
Harry Potter must not go back...
해리 포터는 올해에
...to Hogwarts School of
Witchcraft and Wizardry this year.
호그와트 마법 학교에
돌아가선 안 돼요
There is a plot, a plot to make
most terrible things happen.
아주 끔찍한 일을 벌리려는
음모가 있어요
What terrible things?
Who's plotting them?
끔찍한 일이라니?
누가 음모를 꾸미는데?
Can't say.
말 못해요
- Okay, I understand. You can't
say. - Don't make me talk. L...
- 알았어, 이해해
- 말하게 하지 마세요, 난…
- Dobby. Dobby, put the
lamp down. - Bad Dobby.
- 도비, 램프 내려놔
- 나쁜 도비!
So when they arrive
at the ninth hole...
그래서 9번 홀에 도착하자…
Give me the lamp.
램프 줘!
Dobby, stop!
도비, 그만해!
- Let me go.
- Get in there and keep quiet.
- 놔주세요
- 들어가서 조용히 있어
- What the devil are you doing
up here? - I was just...
- 너 대체 뭐 하고 있는 거냐?
- 그냥…
You just ruined the punch line
of my Japanese golfer joke.
너 때문에 농담을
제대로 마무리 못 했잖아!
Sorry.
죄송해요
One more sound and you'll wish
you'd never been born, boy.
한 번만 더 시끄럽게 했다간
태어난 걸 후회하게 해주마
- And fix that door.
- Yes, sir.
- 그 문 고치고!
- 네
See why I've got to go back?
왜 내가 돌아가야
하는지 봤지?
I don't belong here. I belong
in your world, at Hogwarts.
이 집은 내가 있을 곳이 아니야
호그와트에 가야 해
- It's the only place I've got friends. -
Friends who don't write to Harry Potter?
- 거기에만 내 친구들이 있어
- 편지도 안 쓰는 친구요?
Well, I expect they've been...
그거야 걔네들이…
Hang on. How do you know my friends
haven't been writing to me?
잠깐, 친구들이 편지를
안 보낸 걸 어떻게 알았지?
Harry Potter mustn't
be angry with Dobby.
해리 포터는
도비한테 화내면 안 돼요
Dobby hoped if Harry Potter thought
his friends had forgotten him...
친구들이 해리 포터를
잊었다고 생각하면
...Harry Potter might not want
to go back to school, sir.
학교에 돌아가기
싫어질 것 같았거든요
- Give me those. Now.
- No!
- 그거 이리 내, 당장
- 안돼요!
Dobby, get back here.
도비, 이리 와!
Dobby, please, no.
도비, 제발 그러지 마
Harry Potter must say he's
not going back to school.
해리 포터는 학교로
안 돌아가겠다고 말해야 해요
I can't. Hogwarts is my home.
안돼
호그와트는 내 집이야
Then Dobby must do it, sir,
for Harry Potter's own good.
그럼 도비는 해리 포터를 위해
이렇게 할 수밖에 없어요
It spread as far as the eye could see,
all over the floor of this building.
사방으로 흘러갔죠
바닥이 완전 물바다였어요
One plumber said, "Look
at all that water."
배관공 한 명이
물 좀 보라고 했어요
The second plumber said, "Yes,
and that's just the top of it."
그랬더니 다른 배관공이
그 밑에도 있다고 했죠
I'm so sorry. It's my nephew.
He's very disturbed.
죄송합니다, 제 조카인데
심한 정서 장애가 있어서요
Meeting strangers upsets him.
That's why I kept him upstairs.
낯선 사람을 보면 겁을 내서
위층에만 있게 하죠
You're never going
back to that school.
다시는 학교에
못 돌아갈 줄 알아라
You're never going to see those
freaky friends of yours again. Never!
다시는 그 이상한 친구들도
못 만날 줄 알아! 절대로!
Hiya, Harry.
안녕, 해리
Ron. Fred. George. What
are you all doing here?
론, 프레드, 조지
여긴 웬일이야?
Rescuing you, of course. Now,
come on, get your trunk.
당연히 널 구하러 왔지
빨리 짐 가져와
You better stand back.
물러서 있어
Let's go.
가자
- What was that?
- What was it?
- 무슨 소리야?
- 뭐죠?
Potter!
포터!
Dad, what's going on?
아빠, 무슨 일이에요?
Go. Go. Go.
어서 가!
Dad, hurry up.
아빠, 서둘러요
- Come on.
- Come on, Harry, hurry up.
- 서둘러!
- 빨리 와, 해리
Petunia, he's escaping!
여보, 녀석이 도망쳐!
- I've got you, Harry.
- Come here!
- 내가 잡았어
- 이리 와!
- Let go of me!
- No, boy!
- 놔요!
- 안돼!
You and that bloody pigeon
aren't going anywhere.
너랑 그 망할 새는
아무 데도 못 가!
- Get off!
- Drive!
- 놔요!
- 어서 가!
- Right.
- Right!
- 알았어
- 어서!
No! No! No! No!
안돼! 안돼! 안돼!
Dad!
아빠!
Damn.
젠장
By the way, Harry,
Happy Birthday.
아, 참, 해리
생일 축하해
Come on.
들어가자
Okay, come on.
좋아, 들어와
얼른 와
- Think it'd be all right if we had
some? - Yeah, Mum will never know.
- 이거 먹어도 될까?
- 응, 엄마는 모를 거야
집
It's not much, but it's home.
별로 좋진 않지만
우리 집이야
I think it's brilliant.
아주 훌륭한데
Where have you been?
너희들 대체 어디 갔었냐?
Harry, how wonderful
to see you, dear.
해리, 널 보니 정말 좋구나
Beds empty. No note. Car gone.
침대는 텅 비었지, 차도 없지
메모 한 장 안 남기고
You could have died. You
could have been seen.
너희들 죽을 수도 있었어
들킬 수도 있었고!
Of course, I don't blame
you, Harry, dear.
물론 널 탓하는 건
아니다, 해리
They were starving him, Mum.
There were bars on his window.
해리를 굶기고 있었어요
창문에 쇠창살도 채우고요
Well, you best hope I don't put bars
on your window, Ronald Weasley.
네 창문에나 쇠창살 안 채우길
바라는 게 좋을 거다, 론
Come on, Harry, time for
a spot of breakfast.
가자, 해리
아침밥 먹어야지
Here we are, Harry.
Now, tuck in.
여기 있다, 해리
어서 먹어
That's it. There we go.
그래, 옳지
- Mummy, have you seen my jumper?
- Yes, dear, it was on the cat.
- 엄마, 제 스웨터 봤어요?
- 고양이가 입고 있더라
Hello.
안녕
What did I do?
내가 뭐 잘못했어?
Ginny. She's been talking about you
all summer. A bit annoying, really.
지니는 여름 내내 네 얘기만 했거든
좀 짜증 나더라
- Morning, Weasleys.
- Morning, Dad.
- 나 왔다!
- 어서 오세요, 아빠
- What a night. Nine
raids. Nine! - Raids?
- 밤새 9번이나 수색을 했어
- 수색?
Dad works in the Ministry of Magic, in
the Misuse of Muggle Artifacts Office.
아빠는 마법부의 머글 문화유물
오용 관리과에서 일하셔
Dad loves Muggles, thinks
they're fascinating.
아버지는 머글들을 좋아하셔
흥미롭다고 생각하시지
Well, now.
자, 그럼…
And who are you?
넌 누구냐?
Sorry, sir. I'm Harry, sir.
Harry Potter.
죄송합니다
전 해리라고 해요, 해리 포터요
Good Lord. Are you really?
이런, 정말이냐?
Well, Ron has told us all about you,
of course. When did he get here?
론한테 얘기 많이 들었다
얘는 언제 왔지?
This morning.
오늘 아침에요
Your sons flew that enchanted car of
yours to Surrey and back last night.
애들이 그 마법에 걸린 차를 몰고
서리에 다녀왔답니다
Did you really? How did it go?
정말 그랬니?
차는 잘 움직이던?
I mean... That was very wrong
indeed, boys. Very wrong of you.
아니, 그러니까…
그건 정말 잘못한 짓이지, 그럼
Now, Harry, you must
know all about Muggles.
해리, 넌 머글에 대해
잘 알고 있겠지
Tell me, what exactly is the
function of a rubber duck?
말해다오, 고무 오리의 기능은
정확히 뭐냐?
Well, that'll be
Errol with the post.
에롤이 편지를
갖고 오나 봐요
Fetch it, will you,
Percy, please?
퍼시, 가서 가져오렴
- Errol.
- He's always doing that.
- 에롤
- 맨날 저런다니까
Look, it's our Hogwarts letters.
They've sent us Harry's as well.
호그와트에서 온 편지예요
해리 것도 있네요
Dumbledore must know you're here.
Doesn't miss a trick, that man.
네가 여기 있는 걸 덤블도어가
아나 봐, 빈틈이 없다니까
- No.
- This lot won't come cheap.
- 정말 그래요
- 책값이 만만치 않아요
- The spell books alone are
expensive. - We'll manage.
- 마법서만 해도 엄청 비싸요
- 어떻게든 되겠지
There's only one place we're going
to get all of this. Diagon Alley.
이걸 전부 구할 수 있는 곳은
단 하나야, 다이애건 앨리
Right.
좋아
Here we are, Harry.
You go first, dear.
여기 있다, 해리
너부터 가렴
But Harry's never traveled
by Floo powder before, Mum.
해리는 플루 가루로
여행해 본 적이 없는데요
Floo powder?
플루 가루?
You go first, Ron, so that Harry
can see how it's done. Yes.
론, 그럼 네가
시범을 보여 줘라
In you go.
들어가라
That's it.
그래
Diagon Alley.
다이애건 앨리
You see? It's quite easy, dear.
Don't be afraid. Come on.
봤지? 아주 쉽단다
겁먹지 말고, 이리 와
Come on.
어서
In you go. That's it.
Mind your head.
들어가라, 옳지
머리 조심하고
That's right. Now,
take your Floo powder.
그래, 플루 가루를 집어라
That's it, very good.
옳지, 잘했어
Now, don't forget to speak
very, very clearly.
아주 또렷하게
말해야 해
Diagonally.
다이거낼리
- What did he say, dear?
- Diagonally.
- 쟤가 뭐라고 했어요?
- 다이거낼리
I thought he did.
그런 것 같더라
- Not lost, are you, my dear? - I'm
fine, thank you. I was just going...
- 얘야, 길을 잃었니?
- 아뇨, 괜찮아요, 돌아가려던 참…
Come with us. We'll help
you find your way back.
우리랑 가자
돌아가는 길을 찾아 주지
- No. Please...
- Harry?
- 아니, 됐어요
- 해리?
Hagrid!
해그리드 아저씨!
What do you think you're
doing down here? Come on.
여기서 뭐 하는 거냐?
이리 와!
녹턴 앨리
You're a mess, Harry. Skulking
around Knockturn Alley? Dodgy place.
녹턴 앨리를 돌아다니다니
여긴 안 좋은 곳이야
Don't want no one to see you there.
People will think you're up to no good.
누가 보기라도 하면 어떡해?
나쁜 일을 꾸미는 줄 알 거다
I was lost, I...
길을 잃었던 거예요, 전…
Hang on. What were you
doing down there then?
잠깐, 그러는 아저씨는
거기 왜 갔어요?
Me? I was... I was looking for
Flesh-Eating Slug Repellent.
나? 난… 육식성 민달팽이
살충제를 찾고 있었지
They're ruining all
the school cabbages.
학교 양배추를 모조리
망치고 있거든
Harry. Hagrid.
해리, 해그리드 아저씨!
Hello, Hermione.
안녕, 헤르미온느
- It's so good to see you.
- It's great to see you too.
- 정말 반갑다
- 나도 반가워
What did you do to your glasses?
안경은 어떻게 된 거야?
Oculus Reparo.
오쿨루스 레파로
I definitely need to
remember that one.
그 주문은 꼭 기억해야겠다
You'll be all right now then,
Harry? Right. I'll leave you to it.
이제 괜찮겠냐, 해리?
그럼 난 이만 가마
- Okay, bye.
- Thank you. Bye.
- 네, 가세요
- 고마워요
Come on, everyone's
been so worried.
빨리 와
다들 얼마나 걱정한다고
신비한 나
질데로이 록허트
Harry.
해리!
Thank goodness. We'd hoped you'd
only gone one grate too far.
다행이다, 한 아궁이밖에
지나치지 않았구나
Ladies and gentlemen,
Mr. Gilderoy Lockhart.
신사 숙녀 여러분
질데로이 록허트 씨입니다
Here he is.
저기 온다!
Mum fancies him.
엄마가 저 사람 좋아해
Make way there, please. Let
me by, madam. Thank you.
좀 비켜 주세요
지나갈게요
Excuse me, little girl. This
is for the Daily Prophet.
실례해요, 꼬마 아가씨
'예언자 일보'에서 왔습니다
It can't be. Harry Potter?
이럴 수가… 해리 포터?
Harry Potter!
해리 포터!
Excuse me, madam.
실례해요, 부인
Nice big smile, Harry. Together,
you and I rate the front page.
크게 웃어라, 해리, 우리 둘의
사진이면 1면에 나올 거야
Ladies and gentlemen, what an
extraordinary moment this is.
신사 숙녀 여러분
정말 굉장한 순간입니다
When young Harry stepped into
Flourish and Blotts this morning...
해리가 제 자서전
'신비한 나'를 사려고
...to purchase my
autobiography, Magical Me...
이 서점까지 왔다니 말이죠
...which, incidentally, is
currently celebrating...
제 자서전은 '예언자 일보'의
베스트셀러 목록에서
...its 27th week atop the Daily
Prophet bestseller list...
현재 27주간 정상을
차지하고 있는데요
...he had no idea that he
would, in fact, be leaving...
해리는 전혀 예상하지
못했겠지만…
...with my entire
collected works...
선물로 제 작품 전집을
모두 선사하겠습니다
...free of charge.
공짜로 말이죠
Now, ladies?
자, 숙녀분들, 오세요
Harry, now you give me those,
and I'll get them signed.
해리, 이리 주렴
내가 가서 사인받아 줄게
All of you wait outside.
That's it.
너희들은 밖에서 기다려
I'll bet you loved that,
didn't you, Potter?
아주 기분 좋았겠네, 포터
Famous Harry Potter. Can't go into a
bookshop without making the front page.
유명하신 해리 포터!
서점에만 가도 신문 1면에 나오는군
Leave him alone.
그냥 놔둬
Look, Potter. You've got
yourself a girlfriend.
이것 봐, 포터
여자 친구가 생겼네
Now, now, Draco, play nicely.
드레이코, 얌전하게 굴어야지
Mr. Potter.
포터 군
Lucius Malfoy. We meet at last.
난 루시우스 말포이다
드디어 만나게 됐군
Forgive me.
잠깐 실례
Your scar is legend.
네 흉터는 전설적이란다
As, of course, is the
wizard who gave it to you.
그걸 네게 준
마법사도 그렇고
Voldemort killed my parents.
볼드모트는
우리 부모님을 죽였어요
He was nothing more
than a murderer.
그는 살인자에 불과해요
You must be very brave
to mention his name.
그의 이름을 언급하다니
아주 용감하군
Or very foolish.
아니면 아주 바보던가
Fear of a name only increases
fear of the thing itself.
이름을 두려워하는 건
두려움만 크게 만들 뿐이죠
And you must be Miss Granger.
그레인저 양인가 보군
Yes, Draco has told me all
about you. And your parents.
드레이코에게 얘기 들었다
네 부모님 얘기도 말이야
Muggles, aren't they?
머글들이지?
Let me see. Red hair,
vacant expressions...
어디 보자
빨강 머리, 얼빠진 표정…
...tatty, secondhand book.
초라한 행색, 중고 책
You must be the Weasleys.
위즐리 가족이 분명하군
It's mad in here.
Let's go outside.
여긴 난장판이구나
밖으로 나가자
- Well, well, well.
- Weasley senior. - Lucius.
- 위즐리 가족의 가장이시군
- 루시우스
Busy time at the Ministry,
Arthur, all those extra raids?
마법부에서 바쁘겠군, 아서
단속을 많이 한다지?
I do hope they're
paying you overtime...
초과 수당을
받고 있길 바라네
...but judging by the state
of this, I'd say not.
그런데 꼬락서니를 보니
못 받는 것 같군
What's the use in being a
disgrace to the name of wizard...
돈도 제대로 못 받을 거면서
...if they don't even
pay you well for it?
뭐하러 마법사의 이름에
먹칠을 하나?
We have a very different idea about what
disgraces the name of wizard, Malfoy.
말포이, 자네랑 난 마법사의 이름에
먹칠하는 게 뭔지에 대한 생각이 달라
Clearly.
그러게 말이야
Associating with Muggles.
머글 따위와 어울리다니
And I thought your family
could sink no lower.
자네 가족은 완전히
밑바닥까지 내려갔군
I'll see you at work.
일터에서 보세
See you at school.
학교에서 보자
- 10:58, come on. - The train
will be leaving any moment.
- 10시 58분이야, 서둘러
- 기차가 곧 떠날 거야
Fred, George, Percy, you first.
프레드, 조지, 퍼시
너희들부터 가라
Okay.
좋아
After you, dear.
당신 먼저 가
Come on, Ginny, we'll
get you a seat. Hurry.
어서 가자, 지니
자리 잡아 줄게
Let's go.
가자
- What do you two think
you're doing? - Sorry.
- 너희들 무슨 짓이야?
- 죄송해요
Lost control of the trolley.
손수레가 제멋대로 가서요
- Why can't we get through?
- I don't know.
- 우리는 왜 못 들어가?
- 나도 몰라
The gateway has sealed
itself for some reason.
왜 그런지 모르겠는데
통로가 막혔어
The train leaves at exactly
11:00. We've missed it.
기차는 정확히 11시에
떠난단 말이야, 놓쳐 버렸어
Harry, if we can't
get through...
해리, 우리가 여길
통과할 수 없다면
...maybe Mum and Dad
can't get back.
엄마랑 아빠도
못 돌아올지 몰라
Maybe we should just go
and wait by the car.
가서 차 옆에서 기다리자
The car.
자동차?
Ron, I should tell you...
론, 할 얘기가 있어
...most Muggles aren't accustomed
to seeing a flying car.
머글들은 하늘을 나는 차를
보는 데 익숙하지 않아
Right.
알았어
Okay.
좋아
Oh, no! The Invisibility
Booster must be faulty.
이런! 투명 부스터가
고장 났나 봐
Come on, then. Let's go lower.
We need to find the train.
그럼 밑으로 내려가자
기차를 찾아야 해
Okay.
알았어
All we need to do is
catch up with the train.
기차만 따라잡으면 돼
We can't be far behind.
가까이 있을 거야
- Do you hear that?
- We must be getting close.
- 들려?
- 가까이 왔나 보다
Hold on.
잠깐만
호그와트 급행열차
Harry!
해리!
Hold on!
꽉 잡아!
Take my hand!
내 손을 잡아!
Hold on!
잡아!
I'm trying. Your
hand's all sweaty.
노력하는 중이야
네 손이 땀 투성이란 말이야
- I think we found the train.
- Yeah.
- 기차는 찾은 것 같다
- 그래
Welcome home.
집에 온 걸 환영해
Up! Up!
위! 위로 가!
It's not working!
작동이 안 돼!
Up! Ron, mind that tree!
위로 가! 나무 조심해!
Stop! Stop! Stop!
멈춰! 멈춰!
- My wand. Look at my wand. -
Be thankful it's not your neck.
- 내 요술 지팡이 좀 봐!
- 목이 안 부러진 걸 감사해
- What's happening?
- I don't know.
- 어떻게 된 거야?
- 나도 몰라
Come on, go! Fast!
출발해! 어서!
Scabbers, you're okay.
스캐버스, 괜찮았구나
The car!
자동차!
Dad's gonna kill me.
아빠가 날 죽일 거야
See you, Hedwig.
나중에 보자, 헤드위그
So a house-elf shows
up in my bedroom...
꼬마 집요정 하나가
내 방에 나타나고
...we can't get through the
barrier to platform 93/4...
역에서는 통로로
들어가지도 못했어
...we almost get
killed by a tree...
나무한테
맞아 죽을 뻔하고…
Clearly someone doesn't
want me here this year.
누군가 내가 여기 오는 걸
바라지 않는 것 같아
Well, take a good look, lads.
잘 보렴, 얘들아
This night might well be the
last you spend in this castle.
오늘 밤이 이 성에서 보내는
마지막이 될 테니
Oh, dear, we are in trouble.
이런, 정말 큰일 났군
You were seen by no less
than seven Muggles.
7명 이상의 머글이
너희들을 목격했어
Do you have any idea
how serious this is?
이게 얼마나 심각한
문제인지 알아?
You have risked the
exposure of our world.
우리 세계가
탄로날 뻔했다고
Not to mention the damage you
inflicted on a Whomping Willow...
너희가 태어나기 전부터
여기 있던
...that's been on these grounds
since before you were born.
커다란 버드나무에 피해를 입힌 건
말할 것도 없고!
Honestly, Professor Snape, I
think it did more damage to us.
버드나무가 우리에게
더 피해를 입혔는데요
Silence.
조용!
I assure you that were you in Slytherin,
and your fate rested with me...
너희들이 슬리데린 학생이고
너희들 운명이 내게 달렸다면
...the both of you would be
on the train home tonight.
오늘 밤 기차를 태워
집으로 돌려보낼 거다
- As it is...
- They are not.
- 하지만…
- 그렇지가 않지
Professor Dumbledore.
Professor McGonagall.
덤블도어 교수님
맥고나걸 교수님
Headmaster...
교장 선생님
...these boys have flouted the Decree for
the Restriction of Underage Wizardry.
이 아이들은 미성년 마법사의
행동 제한 법령을 어겼습니다
- As such... - I am well
aware of our bylaws...
- 따라서…
- 나도 법은 잘 아네, 세베루스
...having written quite
a few of them myself.
몇 가지 법은
내가 직접 썼으니까 말이지
However, as head of
Gryffindor house...
하지만 조치를 취하는 건
그리핀도르 기숙사의
...it is for Professor McGonagall to
determine the appropriate action.
담당 교수인 맥고나걸 교수가
해야 할 일이야
We'll go and get
our stuff, then.
우린 가서 짐 쌀게요
What are you talking
about, Mr. Weasley?
무슨 말이지, 위즐리 군?
You're going to expel
us, aren't you?
저희들 퇴학시키실 거죠?
Not today, Mr. Weasley...
오늘은 아니야
...but I must impress on both of you
the seriousness of what you have done.
하지만 이게 얼마나 심각한 일인지
깨닫게 해줘야겠지
I will be writing to your families tonight,
and you will both receive detention.
둘 다 방과 후에 벌을 주겠다
가족에게는 편지로 알리마
Morning, everyone.
안녕, 여러분
- Good morning, everyone. -
Good morning, Professor Sprout.
- 안녕, 여러분!
- 안녕하세요, 스프라우트 교수님
Welcome to Greenhouse Three, second
years. Gather around, everyone.
2학년들, 3번 온실로 환영해요
다들 모여 봐요
Today we're going to
re-pot Mandrakes.
오늘은 맨드레이크를
분갈이해 줄 거예요
Who here can tell me the
properties of the Mandrake root?
맨드레이크 뿌리의 특성을
말해 볼 사람?
Yes, Miss Granger?
그래, 그레인저
Mandrake, or Mandragora...
'맨들라고라'라고도 불리는
맨드레이크는
...is used to return those who have
been Petrified to their original state.
돌처럼 굳어진 사람을 원상태로
돌려놓는 데 사용됩니다
It's also dangerous. The Mandrake's
cry is fatal to anyone who hears it.
또 위험한 풀이죠, 맨드레이크의 비명은
듣는 사람에겐 치명적이에요
Excellent. Ten points
to Gryffindor.
훌륭해요
그리핀도르에 10점
As our Mandrakes are
still only seedlings...
여기 있는 맨드레이크는
아직 새싹이기 때문에
...their cries won't
kill you yet.
비명 소리로
누굴 죽이지는 못해요
But they could knock you out for hours,
which is why I have given you earmuffs...
하지만 몇 시간쯤 정신을
잃을 수는 있기 때문에
...for auditory protection.
귀마개를 준 거예요
So could you please put them
on, right away? Quickly.
이제 귀마개를 쓰세요
어서요
Flaps tight down, and
watch me closely.
단단히 막고
선생님을 잘 봐요
You grasp your Mandrake firmly.
맨드레이크를 꽉 잡고
You pull it sharply
up out of the pot.
세게 잡아당겨서
화분에서 빼내요
Got it? And...
알겠어요? 그리고…
...now you dunk it down
into the other pot...
다른 화분에 집어넣고
...and pour a little sprinkling
of soil to keep him warm.
흙을 뿌려서
따뜻하게 해줘요
Longbottom's been
neglecting his earmuffs.
롱바텀은 귀마개를 안 했군
- No, ma'am, he's just fainted. -
Yes, well, just leave him there.
- 아뇨, 그냥 기절한 건데요
- 그래, 그냥 놔둬
Right, on we go. Plenty
of pots to go around.
그럼 시작하죠
화분은 충분해요
Grasp your Mandrake
and pull it up.
맨드레이크를 잡고
잡아당겨 뽑으세요
- There's Nearly Headless Nick.
- Hello, Percy, Miss Clearwater.
- '목이 달랑달랑한 닉'이다
- 안녕, 퍼시, 클리어워터 양
Hello, Sir Nicholas.
안녕하세요, 니콜라스 경
Say it. I'm doomed.
말해 봐, 난 이제 끝이야
- You're doomed.
- Hi, Harry.
- 넌 끝이야
- 안녕, 해리
I'm Colin Creevey. I'm
in Gryffindor too.
콜린 크리비라고 해
나도 그리핀도르야
Hi, Colin. Nice to meet you.
안녕, 만나서 반갑다
Ron, is that your owl?
론, 저거 네 부엉이야?
Bloody bird's a menace.
골칫덩어리 새 같으니!
Oh, no.
이런!
Look, everyone. Weasley's
got himself a Howler.
저것 봐, 얘들아
위즐리가 호울러를 받았어
Go on, Ron. I ignored one from
my gran once. It was horrible.
나도 할머니한테 한 번 받았는데
무시했다가 죽을 뻔했어
Ronald Weasley!
로널드 위즐리!
How dare you steal that car!
I am absolutely disgusted!
감히 차를 훔치다니!
내가 진짜 못 살아!
Your father's now facing
an inquiry at work...
아빠가 직장에서
문책을 받게 됐는데
...nd it's entirely
your fault!
전부 네 잘못이야!
If you put another
toe out of line...
한 번만 더 사고 쳤다간
...we'll bring you
straight home!
당장 집으로 끌고 오겠어!
And, Ginny, dear, congratulations
on making Gryffindor.
그리고 지니, 그리핀도르에
들어간 걸 축하한다
Your father and
I are so proud.
아빠랑 난 네가
정말 자랑스럽단다
Let me introduce you to your new
Defense Against the Dark Arts teacher.
어둠의 마법 방어술을 가르칠
새 선생님을 소개하겠다
Me.
바로 나란다
Gilderoy Lockhart...
나는 질데로이 록허트
...Order of Merlin,
Third Class...
멀린 3등급 훈장 수여자이며
...honorary member of the
Dark Force Defense League...
'어둠의 힘 방어 연맹'의
명예 회원이지
...and five times winner...
그리고 '마녀 주간지'가
선정하는
...of Witch Weekly's
Most-Charming-Smile Award.
'가장 매력적인 미소 상'을
5번이나 받았고
But I don't talk about that.
하지만 난 그런 얘긴 안 해
I didn't get rid of the Bandon
Banshee by smiling at him.
내가 미소로 밴던 밴시를
없앤 건 아니니까
Now, be warned.
자, 새겨 들어라
It is my job to arm you...
내 임무는 여러분이
가장 악랄한
...against the foulest
creatures known to wizardkind.
괴물과 맞설 수 있도록
여러분을 무장시키는 것이다
You may find yourselves facing
your worst fears in this room.
너희들은 이 교실에서
엄청난 공포와 마주할 것이다
Know only that no harm can
befall you whilst I am here.
하지만 내가 여기 있는 한
아무런 위험도 없다는 걸 알아 둬라
I must ask you not to scream.
비명은 지르지 말도록
It might provoke them.
그건 녀석들을
자극할 테니까 말이야
Cornish pixies?
콘월의 작은 요정들이잖아?
Freshly caught Cornish pixies.
막 잡아 온 콘월의
작은 요정들이지
Laugh if you will,
Mr. Finnegan...
웃고 싶으면 웃어라
피니간 군
...but pixies can be devilishly
tricky little blighters.
하지만 이놈들은 사악하고
교활한 녀석들이야
Let's see what you make of them.
너희들이 어떻게
대처하는지 보자
Come on now, round them up.
They're only pixies.
자, 몰아 봐라
단순한 요정들이야
- You just stay there!
- Please, get me down!
- 넌 거기 있어
- 내려 줘!
- Get off me!
- Stop. Hold still!
- 저리 가!
- 가만히 있어!
Peskipiksi Pesternomi!
페스키픽시 페스테르노미!
I'll ask you three to just nip the
rest of them back into their cage.
너희 셋이서 저놈들을
우리에 다시 가둬라
What do we do now?
이제 어쩌지?
Immobulus!
이모뷸러스!
Why is it always me?
왜 맨날 나야?
I spent the summer devising a
whole new Quidditch program.
여름 내내 새로운 퀴디치
프로그램을 고안했어
We're gonna train earlier,
harder and longer.
더 일찍 시작해서 더 긴 기간 동안
더 열심히 연습하는 거야
What...? I don't believe it.
저게 뭐야? 내가 미쳐
- Where you think you're going,
Flint? - Quidditch practice.
- 어디 가는 거야, 플린트?
- 퀴디치 연습하러
- I booked the pitch for Gryffindor
today. - Easy, Wood. I've got a note.
- 오늘은 그리핀도르가 예약했어
- 나 허락받았어
I smell trouble.
뭔가 심상치 않은데
"I, Professor Severus Snape, do
hereby give the Slytherin team...
"나, 세베루스 스네이프 교수는
슬리데린 팀에게"
...permission to practice today, owing
to the need to train their new Seeker."
"새로운 수색꾼의 훈련을 위해
오늘 연습할 것을 허락한다"
You've got a new Seeker. Who?
새로운 수색꾼이 생겼어?
누군데?
- Malfoy?
- That's right.
- 말포이?
- 그래
And that's not all
that's new this year.
새로 들어온 게 또 있지
Those are Nimbus 2001 s.
How did you get those?
'님부스 2001'이잖아
어디서 났어?
A gift from Draco's father.
드레이코의 아버지가
선물로 주셨어
You see, Weasley, unlike some,
my father can afford the best.
위즐리, 우리 아빠는 최고급 물건을
살 수 있어, 누구랑 달리 말이야
At least no one on the Gryffindor
team had to buy their way in.
그리핀도르 팀원들 중에는
돈으로 들어온 사람 없어
They got in on pure talent.
실력만으로 들어온 거야
No one asked your opinion,
you filthy little Mudblood.
너한테 안 물었거든?
더러운 잡종 계집애
You'll pay for that one, Malfoy.
Eat slugs!
그 말 후회할 거야, 말포이
민달팽이나 먹어라!
You okay, Ron?
괜찮아, 론?
Say something.
뭐라고 말 좀 해봐
- Wow! Can you turn him around, Harry?
- No, Colin, get out of the way.
- 우와! 얼굴 좀 돌려 봐
- 콜린, 저리 가!
Let's take him to Hagrid's.
해그리드한테 데려가자
He'll know what to do.
어떻게 해야 할지
아실 거야
This calls for a
specialist's equipment.
특별한 장비가 필요하겠구나
Nothing to do but wait
till it stops, I'm afraid.
멈출 때까지
기다리는 수밖에 없겠어
- Okay.
- Better out than in.
- 잘했어
- 삼키는 것보다 뱉는 게 낫지
- Who was Ron trying to curse, anyway?
- Malfoy. He called Hermione...
- 론이 누굴 저주하려고 한 거냐?
- 말포이요, 헤르미온느한테…
Well, I don't know
exactly what it means.
뭐라고 했는데 무슨 뜻인지
잘 모르겠어요
He called me a Mudblood.
저더러 잡종이랬어요
- He did not.
- What's a Mudblood?
- 설마…
- 잡종이 뭐예요?
It means "dirty blood. " Mudblood's a
foul name for someone who's Muggle-born.
'더러운 피'란 뜻이야
머글 태생을 천하게 부르는 말이지
Someone with non-magic parents.
Someone like me.
부모가 마법사가 아닌 사람
나 같은 사람 말이야
It's not a term one usually hears
in civilized conversation.
교양 있는 대화에서는
잘 들을 수 없는 말이지
See, the thing is, Harry, there are
some wizards, like the Malfoy family...
해리, 말포이 가문 같은
일부 마법사들은
...who think they're better than everyone
else because they're pure-blood.
자기들은 순수 혈통이니까
남들보다 나은 줄 안단다
That's horrible.
그건 나빠요!
It's disgusting.
구역질 나요
And it's codswallop to boot.
Dirty blood.
더러운 피라니 웃기는 소리야
Why, there isn't a wizard alive today
that's not half-blood or less.
지금은 다른 피가 조금도
안 섞인 마법사는 없거든
More to the point, they've yet to think
of a spell that our Hermione can't do.
게다가 우리 헤르미온느는
못하는 주문이 없잖니
Come here.
이리 오렴
Don't you think on it, Hermione. Don't
you think on it for one minute.
헤르미온느, 그런 건 조금도
마음에 두지 마라
Harry, Harry, Harry.
해리, 해리, 해리
Can you possibly imagine...
생각해 봐라
...a better way to
serve detention...
내 팬레터에 답장 쓰는 걸
도와주는 것보다
...than by helping me
to answer my fan mail?
더 멋진 벌이
어디 있겠니?
Not really.
없는 것 같네요
Fame is a fickle friend, Harry.
Celebrity is as celebrity does.
명성은 변덕스러운 친구란다
유명인이 하는 일이 곧 유명세지
Remember that.
명심해라
Come.
오너라
Come...
...to me.
내게로…
- What?
- Sorry?
- 뭐지?
- 뭐라고?
That voice.
저 목소리요
Voice?
목소리?
- Didn't you hear it? - What
are you talking about, Harry?
- 못 들으셨어요?
- 무슨 말이냐, 해리?
I think you're getting
a bit drowsy.
슬슬 졸리기 시작하나 보군
And great Scott, no wonder. Look at the
time. We've been here nearly four hours.
그럴 만도 하지
벌써 4시간째 있었으니
Spooky how the time flies
when one is having fun.
재미있는 일을 할 때는
시간이 얼마나 빠른지 무섭다니까
Spooky.
무섭네요
Blood.
피
I smell blood.
피 냄새가 나
Let me rip you.
내가 갈기갈기 찢어 주마
Let me kill you.
내가 죽여주지
Kill!
죽여!
- Kill!
- Harry!
- 죽여!
- 해리!
- Did you hear it?
- Hear what?
- 들었어?
- 뭘 들어?
- That voice.
- Voice? What voice?
- 목소리 말이야
- 무슨 목소리?
I heard it first in Lockhart's
office. And then again just...
록허트 교수님 방에서
처음 들었는데 방금 또…
It's time.
시간이 됐다
It's moving. I think
it's going to kill.
움직이고 있다
죽이려는 것 같아
- Kill?
- Harry, wait! Not so fast!
- 죽여?
- 해리, 기다려! 천천히 가!
Strange.
이상하네
- I've never seen spiders act like
that. - I don't like spiders.
- 거미들이 저러는 건 처음 봐
- 난 거미 싫어
What's that?
저게 뭐야?
"The Chamber of Secrets has been
opened. Enemies of the Heir, beware."
"비밀의 방이 열렸다
후계자의 적들이여, 조심하라"
It's written in blood.
피로 쓴 거야
Oh, no.
맙소사
It's Filch's cat.
필치의 고양이야
It's Mrs. Norris.
노리스 부인
"Enemies of the Heir, beware."
"후계자의 적들이여, 조심하라"
You'll be next, Mudbloods.
다음은 너희들이야, 잡종들
What's going on here? Go on.
Make way, make way.
무슨 일이야?
저리 비켜
Potter?
포터?
What are you...?
대체 뭘 하고…
Mrs. Norris?
노리스 부인?
- You've murdered my cat.
- No. No.
- 내 고양이를 죽였군
- 아니에요
I'll kill you.
죽여 버리겠어
- I'll kill you!
- Argus!
- 죽여 버리겠어!
- 아구스!
Argus, I...
아구스, 내가…
Everyone will proceed to their
dormitories immediately.
다들 당장 기숙사로
돌아가세요
Everyone except...
거기…
...you three.
세 명은 빼고
Ravenclaws, follow me.
래번클로는 날 따라와요
She's not dead, Argus.
She has been Petrified.
죽은 게 아니라
굳어 버린 걸세, 아구스
Thought so. So unlucky
I wasn't there.
그럴 줄 알았죠
내가 있었어야 하는 건데
I know exactly the countercurse
that could've spared her.
제가 아는 반대 주문으로
구할 수 있었다고요
But how she has been
Petrified, I cannot say.
어떻게 굳어 버렸는지는
모르겠군
Ask him. It's him
that's done it.
저 녀석에게 물어보세요
저 녀석 짓이니까
You saw what he
wrote on the wall.
벽에 써 놓은 걸 보셨잖아요
It's not true, sir. I swear.
I never touched Mrs. Norris.
전 맹세코 아니에요
고양이를 만진 적도 없어요
- Rubbish.
- If I might, headmaster?
- 웃기지 마!
- 제가 한 말씀 드리죠
Perhaps Potter and his friends were just
in the wrong place at the wrong time.
포터와 친구들은 단지 안 좋은 때
안 좋은 곳에 있었던 걸지도 모르죠
However...
그렇지만…
...the circumstances
are suspicious.
상황은 확실히 의심스럽군요
I, for one, don't recall
seeing Potter at dinner.
전 저녁 식사 때
포터를 본 기억이 없거든요
I'm afraid that's
my doing, Severus.
그건 저 때문입니다, 세베루스
You see, Harry was helping
me answer my fan mail.
제 팬레터에 답장을
쓰는 걸 돕고 있었거든요
That's why Ron and I went
looking for him, Professor.
그래서 론과 제가
해리를 찾으러 다녔던 거예요
We'd just found him
when he said...
그래서 찾아냈는데
해리가 말하길…
- Yes, Miss Granger?
- When I said I wasn't hungry.
- 말해 봐, 그레인저
- 전 배고프지 않다고 했어요
We were heading back to the common
room when we found Mrs. Norris.
휴게실로 돌아가는 길에
노리스 부인을 발견했고요
- Innocent until proven guilty,
Severus. - My cat has been Petrified.
- 죄가 입증되기 전까지는 무죄일세
- 내 고양이가 굳어 버렸어요
- I want to see some punishment! -
We will be able to cure her, Argus.
- 뭔가 처벌을 해야죠!
- 치료할 수 있을 걸세
As I understand it, Madam Sprout has
a very healthy growth of Mandrake.
스프라우트 교수께서
맨드레이크를 잘 키우고 계시니
When matured, a potion will be made
which will revive Mrs. Norris.
다 자라면 그걸로 약을 만들어
노리스 부인을 소생시키면 돼
And in the meantime...
그동안…
...I strongly
recommend caution...
여러분 모두에게 조심할 것을
...to all.
강력하게 권고합니다
- It's a bit strange, isn't it?
- Strange?
- 좀 이상하지 않아?
- 이상하다고?
You hear this voice, a
voice only you can hear...
너한테만 목소리가 들렸고
...and then Mrs. Norris turns up
Petrified. It's just strange.
그 다음에 노리스 부인이
굳어 버렸잖아, 정말 이상해
Do you think I should have told them?
Dumbledore and the others, I mean?
교수님들께 말해야 했을까?
Are you mad?
미쳤어?
No, Harry. Even in the wizarding world,
hearing voices isn't a good sign.
안돼, 마법의 세계에서도
목소리가 들리는 건 나쁜 징조야
She's right, you know.
맞는 말이야
Could I have your
attention, please?
주목해 주세요
Right. Now, today, we will
be transforming animals...
자, 오늘은 동물을 물잔으로
...into water goblets.
변신시켜 보겠어요
Like so.
이렇게요
One, two, three. Vera Verto.
하나, 둘, 셋
베라 베르토
Now it's your turn. Who
would like to go first?
이제 여러분 차례예요
누가 먼저 할까요?
Mr. Weasley. "One, two, three.
Vera Verto. ".
위즐리 군, "하나, 둘, 셋
베라 베르토"라고 하면 돼요
Vera Verto!
베라 베르토!
That wand needs
replacing, Mr. Weasley.
요술 지팡이를
바꿔야겠구나
- Yes, Miss Granger?
- Professor...
- 그래, 그레인저
- 교수님
...I was wondering if you could tell
us about the Chamber of Secrets.
혹시 비밀의 방에 대한 얘기를
해주실 수 있나요?
Very well.
좋아요
You all know, of course...
다들 알다시피
...that Hogwarts was founded
over a thousand years ago...
호그와트는 천 년도 전에
당대 최고의
...by the four greatest witches
and wizards of the age
마녀와 마법사 네 명에 의해
설립됐어요
Godric Gryffindor,
Helga Hufflepuff...
고드릭 그리핀도르
헬가 후플푸프
...Rowena Ravenclaw and
Salazar Slytherin.
로웨나 래번클로, 그리고
살라자르 슬리데린
Now, three of the founders
coexisted quite harmoniously.
창립자들 중 세 명은
조화를 이루며 공존했지만
- One did not.
- Three guesses who.
- 한 명은 안 그랬죠
- 누군지 알겠네
Salazar Slytherin wished
to be more selective...
살라자르 슬리데린은
호그와트 입학생들을
...about the students
admitted to Hogwarts.
보다 까다롭게
선별하고 싶어 했어요
He believed magical learning should
be kept within all-magic families.
마법 교육은 마법사 가문 사이에만
이루어져야 한다고 믿었죠
In other words, pure-bloods.
다시 말해
순수 혈통 말이에요
Unable to sway the others, he
decided to leave the school.
다른 사람들이 동조하지 않자
그는 학교를 떠나기로 했어요
Now, according to legend...
전설에 따르면
...Slytherin had built a hidden
chamber in this castle...
슬리데린은 이 성에 몰래
비밀의 방을 만들었다고
...known as the
Chamber of Secrets.
전해지고 있어요
Though, shortly before
departing, he sealed it...
하지만 그는 떠나기 직전
그 방을 봉했다고 하죠
...until that time when his own
true Heir returned to the school.
자신의 진정한 후계자가
학교로 돌아올 때까지 말이에요
The Heir alone...
오직 후계자만이
...would be able to
open the Chamber...
비밀의 방의 문을 열고
...and unleash the horror
within, and by so doing...
그 안에 있는 공포를
해방시킬 수 있어요
...purge the school
of all those who...
그렇게 함으로써
슬리데린의 관점에서 볼 때
...in Slytherin's view, were
unworthy to study magic.
마법을 배울 자격이 없는
학생들을 정화시킬 예정이었죠
Muggle-borns.
머글 태생 말이군요
Naturally, the school has
been searched many times.
당연히 학교 측은
여러 번 조사를 했지만
No such chamber has been found.
그런 방은 발견되지 않았어요
Professor? What exactly does legend
tell us lies within the Chamber?
교수님, 전설에 의하면
비밀의 방 안에는 뭐가 있나요?
The Chamber is said to
be home to something...
비밀의 방에는
슬리데린의 후계자만이
...that only the Heir of
Slytherin can control.
통제할 수 있는
뭔가가 있다고 해요
It is said to be the home...
전설에 따르면 그곳엔
...of a monster.
괴물이 산다고 하죠
Do you think it's true? Do you think
there really is a Chamber of Secrets?
너희는 비밀의 방이
정말 있다고 생각해?
Yes. Couldn't you tell? McGonagall's
worried. All the teachers are.
당연하지, 못 느꼈어?
선생님들 전부 걱정하고 있어
If there really is a Chamber of Secrets,
and it has been opened, that means...
비밀의 방이 정말 있고
그 문이 열렸다면…
The Heir of Slytherin has returned to
Hogwarts. The question is, who is it?
슬리데린의 후계자가 온 거지
문제는 그게 누구냐야
Let's think. Who do we know who
thinks all Muggle-borns are scum?
글쎄, 머글 태생이 쓰레기라고
생각하는 사람이 누구지?
- If you're talking about Malfoy...
- Of course. You heard him.
- 말포이 얘기라면…
- 당연하지, 쟤가 한 말 들었잖아
"You'll be next, Mudbloods."
"다음은 너희들이야, 잡종들"
I heard him. But Malfoy,
the Heir of Slytherin?
그래, 하지만 말포이가
슬리데린의 후계자라고?
Maybe Ron's right, Hermione.
I mean, look at his family.
론이 맞을지도 몰라
말포이의 가족을 봐
The whole lot of them have been
in Slytherin for centuries.
몇 세기 동안
전부 슬리데린이었잖아
Crabbe and Goyle must know. Maybe
we could trick them into telling.
크레이브와 고일은 알 거야
우리한테 털어놓게 속여 보자
Even they aren't that thick. But
there might be another way.
그렇게 멍청하진 않을걸
다른 방법이 있긴 해
Mind you, it would be difficult.
하지만 어려운 일이야
Not to mention we'd be breaking
about 50 school rules...
교칙을 50개쯤
어기게 되는 건 물론이고
...and it'll be dangerous.
Very dangerous.
아주 아주 위험할 거야
모스트 포텐트 마법의 약
Here it is. The
Polyjuice Potion.
여기 있다
폴리 주스 마법의 약
"Properly brewed, the Polyjuice
Potion allows the drinker...
"제대로 조제된
폴리 주스 마법의 약은"
...to transform himself temporarily
into the physical form of another."
"마신 사람을 일시적으로
다른 사람의 형태로 변화시킨다"
You mean if Harry and I drink that
stuff, we'll turn into Crabbe and Goyle?
해리와 내가 마시면 크레이브와
고일로 변신할 수 있다고?
- Wicked! Malfoy will tell
us anything. - Exactly.
- 멋지다! 말포이가 몽땅 털어놓을걸
- 바로 그거야
But it's tricky. I've never
seen a more complicated potion.
그런데 좀 어려워
나도 이렇게 복잡한 약은 처음 봐
- How long will it take
to make? - A month.
- 만드는 데 얼마나 걸려?
- 한 달
A month?
한 달?
But, Hermione, if Malfoy is
the Heir of Slytherin...
하지만 말포이가 정말
슬리데린의 후계자라면
...he could attack half the
Muggle-borns in the school by then.
그때쯤엔 머글 태생 학생
절반을 공격했을 거야
I know.
나도 알아
But it's the only
plan we've got.
하지만 이 방법밖에 없어
Another goal for Slytherin!
또 다시 슬리데린의
골입니다!
그리핀도르 대 슬리데린
They lead Gryffindor 90 to 30.
슬리데린이 90 대 30으로
앞서고 있습니다!
Yeah!
좋았어!
앗싸!
All right there, Scarhead?
괜찮냐, 흉터 대가리?
Watch yourself, Harry!
조심해, 해리!
Wood, look out!
우드, 조심해!
Blimey! Harry's got
himself a rogue Bludger.
이런! 해리가 날뛰는
블러저에 쫓기고 있군
That's been tampered
with, that has.
누가 손을 댄 게 틀림없어!
I'll stop it.
내가 멈춰 주지
No! Even with a proper wand, it's
too risky. You could hit Harry.
안돼! 멀쩡한 요술 지팡이로도 위험해
해리가 맞을 수도 있다고
Training for the ballet, Potter?
발레 연습하냐, 포터?
You'll never catch me, Potter.
날 절대 못 잡을걸?
Let's go.
가자
Harry Potter has caught the
Snitch. Gryffindor wins!
해리 포터가 스니치를 잡았습니다
그리핀도르 승리!
Finite Incantatem!
피니트 인칸타템!
- Thank you.
- Are you okay?
- 고마워
- 괜찮아?
No. I think my arm is broken.
아니, 팔이 부러진 것 같아
Not to worry, Harry. I will fix
that arm of yours straightaway.
걱정 마라, 해리
내가 당장 고쳐 줄 테니
- Not you. - Boy doesn't
know what he's saying.
- 선생님은 싫어요
- 얘가 횡설수설하네
This won't hurt a bit.
하나도 안 아플 거야
Brackium Emendo!
브라키움 에멘도!
Yes, well, that can
sometimes happen...
아, 그래
가끔 이러기도 한단다
...but the point is...
하지만 중요한 건…
...you can no longer feel any pain, and,
very clearly, the bones are not broken.
이제 고통은 못 느낀다는 거지
뼈는 안 부러졌어
Broken? There's no bones left.
부러져요?
남아 있는 뼈도 없는데?
Much more flexible, though.
하지만 훨씬 유연해졌잖소
Mr. Malfoy, stop making such a
fuss. You can go. Out of my way.
말포이, 엄살 떨지 말고
이제 가라, 다들 비켜
Should have been brought
straight to me.
나한테 곧장 데려왔어야지
I can mend bones in a heartbeat,
but growing them back...
뼈를 고치는 건 쉽지만
다시 자라게 하는 건…
You will be able to, won't you?
할 수 있는 거죠?
I'll be able to, certainly.
But it'll be painful.
당연히 할 수 있지
하지만 아플 거다
You're in for a rough night, Potter.
Regrowing bones is a nasty business.
오늘 밤은 좀 힘들 거다
뼈를 재생시키는 건 힘드니까
What do you expect?
Pumpkin juice?
뭘 기대한 거니?
호박 주스?
Kill.
죽여
Time to kill.
시간이 됐다
Hello.
안녕!
Dobby?
도비!
Harry Potter should
have listened to Dobby.
해리 포터는
도비 말을 들었어야 해요
Harry Potter should have gone back
home when he missed the train.
기차를 놓쳤을 때
집으로 갔어야 했어요
It was you. You stopped the barrier
from letting Ron and me through.
너였구나
네가 역에서 통로를 막았어
Indeed. Yes, sir.
네, 맞아요
- You nearly got Ron and me expelled. -
At least you would be away from here.
- 론과 난 퇴학당할 뻔했어
- 그래도 학교는 떠났을 테죠
Harry Potter must go home.
해리 포터는 집에 가야 해요
Dobby thought his Bludger would be
enough to make Harry Potter see...
도비는 블러저 정도면
충분할 줄 알았는데…
Your Bludger? You made that
Bludger chase after me?
블러저? 블러저가
날 쫓게 만든 게 너야?
Dobby feels most aggrieved, sir.
도비는 정말 괴로웠답니다
Dobby had to iron his hands.
도비는 자기 손을
다리미로 다려야 했어요
You better clear off before my bones
come back, or I might strangle you.
넌 가는 게 좋겠다, 내 뼈가 다 나으면
네 목을 조를지도 몰라
Dobby is used to
death threats, sir.
도비는 죽인다는 협박에는 익숙해요
집에선 하루에 5번씩 듣거든요
Dobby gets them five
times a day at home.
I don't suppose you could tell
me why you're trying to kill me?
네가 왜 날 죽이려고 하는지
말해 줄 수 있어?
Not kill you, sir.
Never kill you.
해리 포터를 죽이려고
하는 게 아니에요, 절대로
Dobby remembers how it was
before Harry Potter triumphed...
도비는 해리 포터가
이름을 말해서는 안 되는 그자를
...over
He-Who-Must-Not-Be-Named.
무찌르기 전의 세상이
어땠는지 기억해요
We house-elves were
treated like vermin, sir.
우리 집요정들은
기생충 취급을 당했죠
Of course, Dobby is still
treated like vermin.
물론 도비는 지금도
기생충 취급을 받지만요
Why do you wear
that thing, Dobby?
도비, 왜 그런 걸
입고 있어?
This, sir? It is a mark of
the house-elf's enslavement.
이거 말이에요? 집요정이
노예임을 상징하는 거예요
Dobby can only be freed if his
master presents him with clothes.
도비는 주인이 옷을 줘야만
자유롭게 될 수 있어요
Listen.
들어 보세요
Listen!
들어 봐요!
Terrible things are about
to happen at Hogwarts.
호그와트에서 끔찍한 일이
벌어지려고 해요
Harry Potter must
not stay here...
해리 포터는
여기 있으면 안 돼요
...now that history
is to repeat itself.
역사가 되풀이되려고 해요
Repeat itself? You mean
this has happened before?
되풀이된다고?
전에도 이런 적이 있어?
I shouldn't have said that.
말하면 안 되는 거였는데!
- Bad Dobby! Bad!
- Stop it!
- 나쁜 도비! 나빠!
- 그만해!
Stop it, Dobby!
그만해, 도비!
Tell me. When did this happen
before? Who's doing it now?
언제 그런 일이 있었어?
지금은 누가 그러는 거지?
Dobby cannot say, sir. Dobby only
wants Harry Potter to be safe.
도비는 말할 수 없어요
해리 포터가 무사하기만 원해요
No, Dobby. Tell me. Who is it?
도비, 나한테 말해 줘
누구야?
Put him here.
여기 눕혀요
- What happened?
- There's been another attack.
- 어떻게 된 거죠?
- 또 공격이 있었소
I think he's been
Petrified, Madam Pomfrey.
이 아이도 마비된 것 같아요
폼프리 부인
Look. Perhaps he managed to
take a picture of his attacker.
봐요, 공격한 사람의 사진을
찍었는지도 몰라요
What can this mean, Albus?
이게 무슨 뜻이죠, 알버스?
It means...
이것은…
...that our students
are in great danger.
우리 학생들이 큰 위험에
빠졌다는 뜻입니다
- What should I tell the staff?
- The truth.
- 선생님들에게는 뭐라고 하죠?
- 진실을 말해요
Tell them Hogwarts
is no longer safe.
호그와트가 더 이상
안전하지 않다고
It is as we feared, Minerva.
우리가 두려워하던 대로요
미네르바
The Chamber of Secrets has
indeed been opened again.
비밀의 방이 또 열린 겁니다
Again? You mean the Chamber of
Secrets has been opened before?
또라니? 비밀의 방이 예전에도
열린 적이 있었단 말이야?
Of course. Don't you see?
당연하지, 모르겠어?
Lucius Malfoy must have opened
it when he was at school here.
루시우스 말포이가 여기서
학생이었을 때 열었을 거야
- Now he's taught Draco
how to do it. - Maybe.
- 그리고 드레이코에게 가르쳐 줬고
- 그럴지도 모르지
We'll have to wait for the
Polyjuice Potion to know for sure.
폴리 주스 약이 완성돼서
확실히 알 때까지 기다려야 해
Enlighten me. Why are we brewing
this potion in broad daylight...
그런데 왜 한낮에
여자 화장실에서
...in the middle of the girls' lavatory?
Don't you think we'll get caught?
약을 만들고 있는 거야?
들킬 것 같지 않아?
No. No one ever comes in here.
아니, 아무도 여긴 안 와
- Why?
- Moaning Myrtle.
- 왜?
- 모우닝 머틀 때문에
Who?
누구?
Moaning Myrtle.
모우닝 머틀 말이야
- Who's Moaning Myrtle?
- I'm Moaning Myrtle.
- 모우닝 머틀이 누구야?
- 바로 나다!
I wouldn't expect
you to know me.
당연히 날 모르겠지
Who would ever talk about
ugly, miserable...
못 생기고, 비참하고
우는 소리나 하는
...moping Moaning Myrtle?
모우닝 머틀 얘기를
누가 하겠어?
She's a little sensitive.
쟤가 좀 예민해
Gather round!
다들 모이도록!
Gather round. Can
everybody see me?
다들 모여라
모두들 내가 보이나?
Can you all hear me?
다들 내 말이 들려?
Excellent.
좋아
In light of the dark
events of recent weeks...
최근 몇 주 동안의 불미스러운
사건들을 비추어 볼 때
...Professor Dumbledore has granted me
permission to start this Dueling Club...
덤블도어 교수님께서는
결투 클럽을 만들어서
...to train you all up in case you
ever need to defend yourselves...
여러분이 자신을 방어해야 할 경우를
대비한 훈련을 받게 허락하셨다
...as I myself have done
on countless occasions.
내가 수없이
그랬던 것처럼 말이야
For full details, see
my published works.
자세한 내용은 출간된
내 저서들을 참조하도록
Let me introduce my assistant...
그럼 내 조수를 소개하겠다
...Professor Snape.
스네이프 교수님
He has sportingly agreed to help
with a short demonstration.
날 도와서 짧은 시범을
보여 주시기로 하셨다
I don't want any of you
youngsters to worry.
너희들은 걱정할 필요가
전혀 없어
You'll still have your Potions master
when I'm through with him. Never fear.
스네이프 교수님은 무사히
돌려보내 드릴 테니까 말이야
One.
하나
Two.
둘
- Three!
- Expelliarmus!
- 셋!
- 엑스펠리아르무스!
- Do you think he's all right?
- Who cares?
- 괜찮으실까?
- 알 게 뭐야
An excellent idea to show
them that, Professor Snape...
학생들에게 그걸 보여 주다니
좋은 생각이군요, 스네이프 교수님
...but if you don't mind me saying, it
was obvious what you were about to do.
하지만 뭘 하려고 했는지
너무 뻔하더군요
If I had wanted to stop you, it
would have been only too easy.
내가 마음만 먹었다면
아주 쉽게 막았을 겁니다
Perhaps it would be prudent to
first teach the students...
학생들에게
악의적인 주문을 막는 법을
...to block unfriendly
spells, Professor.
먼저 가르치는 게
현명할 것 같군요
An excellent suggestion,
Professor Snape.
훌륭한 제안입니다
스네이프 교수님
Let's have a volunteer pair.
Potter, Weasley, how about you?
그럼 자원자를 한 쌍 받아 볼까?
포터와 위즐리, 올라올래?
Weasley's wand causes devastation
with the simplest spells.
위즐리의 요술 지팡이는 간단한
주문으로도 큰 피해를 일으키죠
We'll be sending Potter to the
hospital wing in a matchbox.
포터가 산산조각 나서 병원에
실려 갈지도 모릅니다
Might I suggest someone
from my own house?
우리 기숙사에서
한 명 추천해도 될까요?
Malfoy, perhaps?
말포이는 어때요?
- Good luck, Potter.
- Thank you, sir.
- 행운을 빈다, 포터
- 고맙습니다
Wands at the ready.
요술 지팡이 준비!
- Scared, Potter?
- You wish.
- 무섭냐, 포터?
- 웃기지 마
On the count of three...
셋을 세면
...cast your charms to disarm
your opponent. Only to disarm.
상대를 무장 해제시키는
주문만 말한다, 무장 해제만이야
We don't want any
accidents here. One.
사고가 일어나면 안 되지
하나
- Two.
- Everte Statum!
- 둘
- 에베르테 스타툼!
Rictusempra!
릭투셈프라!
I said disarm only.
무장 해제라고만 했잖아!
Serpensortia!
세르펜소르티아!
Don't move, Potter. I'll
get rid of it for you.
움직이지 마라, 포터
내가 없애 주지
Allow me, Professor Snape.
Alarte Ascendare!
제가 하죠, 스네이프 교수님
알라르테 아센다레!
Vipera Evanesca.
비페라 에바네스카
What are you playing at?
무슨 장난을 치는 거야?
You're a Parselmouth?
Why didn't you tell us?
뱀의 말을 한다고
왜 얘기 안 했어?
- I'm a what?
- You can talk to snakes.
- 내가 뭐라고?
- 뱀이랑 말할 수 있잖아
I know. I accidentally set a python
on my cousin Dudley at the zoo once.
알아, 동물원에서 실수로 비단뱀에게
두들리를 공격하게 한 적이 있어
Once. But so what? I bet loads
of people here can do it.
딱 한 번, 그래서 뭐? 여기 있는
많은 사람이 할 수 있을걸
No, they can't. It's not a
very common gift, Harry.
아니, 그건 아주 드문 능력이야
This is bad.
상황이 나빠
What's bad? If I hadn't told that
snake not to attack Justin...
뭐가 나빠? 내가 저스틴을
공격하지 말라고 안 했으면…
- That's what you said to it.
- You were there. You heard me.
- 네가 한 게 그 얘기구나
- 너도 아까 들었잖아
I heard you speaking
Parseltongue. Snake language.
난 네가 뱀의 말을
하는 걸 들었어
I spoke a different language?
내가 다른 언어를 했다고?
But I didn't realize...
난 몰랐어
How can I speak a language
without knowing I can?
어떻게 나도 모르는 사이에
다른 말을 할 수가 있지?
I don't know, but it sounded like you
were egging the snake on or something.
나도 몰라, 하지만 네가 꼭
뱀을 부추기는 것처럼 들렸어
Harry, listen to me.
해리, 내 말 들어 봐
There's a reason the symbol of
Slytherin house is a serpent.
슬리데린 기숙사의 상징이
뱀인 건 다 이유가 있어
Salazar Slytherin was a Parselmouth.
He could talk to snakes too.
살라자르 슬리데린도
뱀의 말을 할 수 있었어
Exactly.
맞아
Now the whole school's gonna think
you're his great-great-great grandson.
이젠 학교 전체가 네가
그의 자손인 줄 알 거야
But I'm not.
하지만 아니잖아
I can't be.
말도 안 돼
He lived a thousand years ago.
그 사람은
천 년 전에 살았어
For all we know, you could be.
네가 그 자손일
가능성도 있어
I'll see you back
in the common room.
휴게실에서 보자
I want blood.
피를 원해
They all must die.
모두 죽어야 해
Kill.
죽여
죽여라
Kill.
죽여 버려!
Time to kill.
죽일 때가 왔도다
Caught in the act.
딱 걸렸군
I'll have you out
this time, Potter.
이번에는 널
내쫓고 말겠다, 포터
Mark my words.
똑똑히 기억해 둬
No. Mr. Filch! You
don't understand...
아니에요, 필치 씨!
뭔가 오해를…
Professor...
교수님
...I swear I didn't.
제가 안 그랬어요
This is out of my hands, Potter.
이건 내가 해결할
문제가 아니구나
Professor Dumbledore
will be waiting for you.
덤블도어 교수님께서
기다리고 계실 거다
Sherbet Lemon.
레몬 방울
Professor Dumbledore?
덤블도어 교수님?
Bee in your bonnet, Potter?
무슨 생각을
그리 골똘히 하지?
I was just wondering if you
put me in the right house.
네가 날 맞는 기숙사에
넣은 건지 궁금해
Yes. You were particularly
difficult to place.
그래, 특히 네 자리를
정하기가 어려웠지
But I stand by what
I said last year.
하지만 내가 작년에
한 말은 변함없다
You would have done
well in Slytherin.
넌 슬리데린에 들어갔어도
잘했을 거야
You're wrong.
틀렸어
Harry?
해리?
Professor.
교수님
Your bird... There was
nothing I could do.
새가…
손쓸 새가 없었어요
- He just caught fire.
- And about time too.
- 갑자기 불이 붙었어요
- 그럴 때가 됐지
He's been looking
dreadful for days.
요즘 꼴이
영 말이 아니었단다
Pity you had to see
him on a burning day.
하필 타는 날에 보다니
유감이구나
Fawkes is a Phoenix, Harry.
퍽스는 불사조란다, 해리
They burst into flame when it
is time for them to die...
죽을 때가 되면
불꽃으로 타오르지
...and then they are...
그리고는 그 재 속에서
...reborn from the ashes.
다시 부활한단다
Fascinating
creatures, phoenixes.
불사조란 흥미로운 생물이야
They can carry
immensely heavy loads.
아주 무거운 짐도
나를 수 있단다
Their tears have healing powers.
그리고 눈물은
치유력이 있지
Professor Dumbledore, sir!
Wait! Listen!
덤블도어 교수님!
잠깐만요! 들어 보세요
Professor Dumbledore,
sir, it wasn't Harry.
덤블도어 교수님
해리 짓이 아니에요
I'd be prepared to swear it in
front of the Ministry of Magic.
마법부에서 진술하라면
그리하겠습니다
Relax.
진정하게
I do not believe...
난 해리가 누군가를
...that Harry attacked anyone.
- Of course you don't.
- 해쳤다고 믿지 않네
- 그럼요
Right. Well, I'll...
알겠습니다, 그럼 전…
- I'll just wait outside, then.
- Yes.
- 밖에서 기다리죠
- 그러게
- You don't think it was me,
Professor? - No, Harry.
- 제가 아니라고 생각하세요?
- 그럼
I do not think it was you.
네 짓이라고
생각하지 않는다
But I must ask you...
하지만 혹시…
...is there something
you wish to tell me?
뭔가 내게
하고 싶은 말 없니?
No, sir.
없습니다
Nothing.
아무것도요
Very well, then.
그렇다면 좋다
Off you go.
그만 가 보거라
Everything's set. We just need a
bit of who you're changing into.
다 준비됐어, 이젠
변신할 사람의 일부가 필요해
Crabbe and Goyle.
크레이브와 고일
We also need to make sure that
the real Crabbe and Goyle...
그리고 우리가 말포이에게
질문을 하는 동안
...can't burst in on us while
we're interrogating Malfoy.
진짜 크레이브와 고일이
나타나지 못하게 해야 돼
- How?
- I've got it all worked out.
- 어떻게?
- 내가 다 생각해 놨어
I filled these with a
simple Sleeping Draught.
여기에 간단한 수면제를
집어넣었어
Simple, but powerful.
간단하지만
약효는 아주 강하지
Now, once they're asleep...
일단 그 애들이 잠들면
...hide them in the broomstick cupboard
and pull out a few of their hairs...
빗자루 창고에 숨긴 다음
머리카락 몇 가닥을 뽑고
...and put on their uniforms.
걔네 교복을 입는 거야
- Whose hair are you ripping out,
then? - I've already got mine.
- 넌 누구 머리를 뽑을 건데?
- 난 이미 준비했어
Millicent Bulstrode. Slytherin.
밀리센트 벌스트로드
슬리데린 학생이야
I got this off her robes.
걔 옷에 붙은 걸
떼어 냈어
I'm going to go check on
the Polyjuice Potion.
난 폴리 주스 마법의 약을
확인하러 갈게
Make sure that Crabbe
and Goyle find these.
크레이브와 고일이
꼭 이걸 보게 해
Ron, maybe I should do it.
론, 내가 하는 게 낫겠다
Yeah. Right.
그래
Wingardium Leviosa.
윙가디움 레비오사
Cool.
맛있겠다!
How thick could you get?
어쩜 저렇게 멍청하지?
Come on, let's get them.
어서 가자
We'll have exactly one hour before
we change back into ourselves.
정확히 한 시간 뒤에
원래 모습으로 돌아올 거야
Add the hairs.
머리카락을 넣어
Essence of Crabbe.
크레이브의 에센스라니!
Cheers.
건배
I think I'm gonna be sick.
토할 것 같아
Me too.
나도
Harry?
해리?
Ron.
론
Bloody hell!
세상에 맙소사!
We still sound like ourselves.
목소리는 그대로야
You need to sound
more like Crabbe.
크레이브처럼 말해 봐
- Bloody hell.
- Excellent.
- 세상에 맙소사
- 잘했어
- But where's Hermione?
- I...
- 헤르미온느는?
- 난…
I don't think I'm going.
You go on without me.
난 못 가겠어
너희들끼리 가
Hermione, are you okay?
헤르미온느, 괜찮아?
Just go. You're wasting time.
얼른 가!
시간 낭비하지 말고
Come on.
가자
I think the Slytherin
common room's this way.
슬리데린 휴게실은
이쪽일 거야
Excuse me.
너희들!
What are you doing d...?
형은 여기서 뭐 하는…
I mean, what are you
doing down here?
넌 거기서 뭐 하냐?
I happen to be a school prefect.
난 반장이잖아
You, on the other hand, have no business
wandering the corridors at night.
너희들은 왜 허락도 없이
오밤중에 복도를 돌아다녀?
What are your names again?
너희들, 이름이 뭐지?
- I'm... - Crabbe, Goyle,
where have you been?
- 내 이름은…
- 크레이브, 고일! 어디 있었어?
Pigging out in the Great
Hall all this time?
지금까지 식당에서
돼지처럼 먹고 있었던 거야?
Why are you wearing glasses?
넌 왜 안경을 쓰고 있어?
- Reading.
- Reading?
- 책 읽느라
- 책을 읽어?
I didn't know you could read.
네가 글을
아는 줄은 몰랐다
And what are you doing
down here, Weasley?
여기서 뭐 하냐, 위즐리?
Mind your attitude, Malfoy.
말 조심해, 말포이
Well, sit down.
뭐해? 앉아
You'd never know the Weasleys were
pure-bloods, the way they behave.
위즐리가 순수 혈통이라니
하는 꼴을 보면 믿기지 않아
They're an embarrassment to the
wizarding world. All of them.
위즐리 가는 전부
마법 세계의 수치야
What's wrong with you, Crabbe?
왜 그래, 크레이브?
Stomachache.
배가 아파서
I'm surprised the Daily Prophet hasn't
done a report on all these attacks.
'예언자 일보'에 공격 사건에 대한
기사가 안 났다니 놀랐어
I suppose Dumbledore is
trying to hush it all up.
덤블도어가 조용히
덮어 버리려는 거겠지
Father always said Dumbledore
was the worst thing...
아버지가 늘 말씀하셨어
덤블도어는
...that ever happened to
this place. - You're wrong!
- 호그와트 최악의 교장이라고
- 아니야!
What?
뭐?
You think there's someone here
who's worse than Dumbledore?
그럼 덤블도어보다
더 형편없는 사람이 있다고?
Well? Do you?
그런 뜻이야?
Harry Potter?
해리 포터?
Good one, Goyle.
맞는 말이야, 고일
You're absolutely right.
그렇고말고!
Saint Potter.
성자 포터!
And people actually think that
he's the Heir of Slytherin?
그 녀석이
슬리데린의 후계자라고?
But then you must have some
idea who's behind it all.
넌 배후에 누가 있는지
알 거 아냐?
You know I don't, Goyle.
I told you yesterday.
나도 몰라, 고일
어제도 말했잖아
How many times do I
have to tell you?
몇 번이나 말해야 돼?
Is this yours?
이거 네 거야?
But my father did say this.
하지만 우리 아버지가
이건 말해 주셨어
It's been 50 years since
the Chamber was opened.
그 방이 열린 지
50년이 됐다고
He wouldn't tell me who opened it.
Only that they were expelled.
그걸 누가 열었는지는
말씀 안 하셨지만 퇴학당했대
The last time the Chamber of Secrets
was opened, a Mudblood died.
마지막으로 비밀의 방이 열렸을 땐
잡종 한 명이 죽었어
So it's only a matter of time before
one of them is killed this time.
그러니 이번에도 그들 중 한 명이
죽는 건 시간문제야
As for me...
난 그게…
...I hope it's Granger.
그레인저였으면 좋겠어
What's the matter with you two?
너희 둘, 대체 왜 그래?
You're acting very odd.
오늘따라 이상하게 굴잖아
It's his stomachache.
배가 아파서 그래
Calm down.
진정해
Scar.
흉터…
Hair.
머리가…
Hey! Where are you going?
야! 어디 가?
That was close.
들킬 뻔했어
Hermione, come out. We've
got loads to tell you.
헤르미온느, 나와
할 이야기가 산더미야
Go away.
저리 가!
Wait till you see. It's awful.
한 번 봐
정말 끔찍해
Hermione?
헤르미온느?
Are you okay?
괜찮아?
Do you remember
me telling you...
내가 폴리 주스 마법의 약은
...that the Polyjuice Potion was
only for human transformations?
사람으로 변신할 때만
쓰는 거라고 했지?
It was cat hair I plucked off
Millicent Bulstrode's robes.
내가 밀리센트의 옷에서
떼낸 건 고양이 털이었어
Look at my face.
내 얼굴 좀 봐
Look at your tail.
꼬리도 있네!
Have you spoken to Hermione?
헤르미온느랑 얘기해 봤어?
She should be out of
hospital in a few days...
며칠 있으면
병원에서 나올 거야
...when she stops
coughing up fur balls.
아직 털을 뱉어 내고 있거든
What's this?
이게 뭐지?
Yuck!
Looks like Moaning Myrtle's
flooded the bathroom.
모우닝 머틀이 화장실 물을
넘치게 했나 봐
- Come to throw something else at me?
- Why would I throw something at you?
- 나한테 또 뭘 던지러 왔어?
- 왜 너한테 뭘 던져?
Don't ask me. Here I am,
minding my own business...
난들 아니?
난 여기 가만히 있는데
...and someone thinks it's
funny to throw a book at me.
누군가 나한테 책 던지는 게
재미있다고 생각했나 봐
But it can't hurt if someone
throws something at you.
그래도 아프진 않을 거 아냐
I mean, it'll just go
right through you.
널 그냥 통과할 테니까
Sure! Let's all throw books at
Myrtle because she can't feel it.
그래! 못 느낄 테니까
다들 책을 던지자 이거지!
Ten points if you get
it through her stomach!
배를 통과하면 10점!
Fifty points if it
goes through her head!
머리를 통과하면 50점!
- But who threw it at you, anyway?
- I don't know. I didn't see them.
- 근데 누가 그랬어?
- 나도 몰라, 못 봤거든
I was just sitting in the
U-bend, thinking about death...
죽음에 대해 생각하며
수도관 속에 앉아 있었는데
...and it fell through
the top of my head.
내 머리를 통과해서 떨어졌어
"Tom Marvolo Riddle."
톰 마볼로 리들
My name...
내 이름은
...is Harry...
해리…
...Potter.
포터입니다
안녕, 해리 포터
내 이름은 톰 리들이야
Do you know anything...
혹시 비밀의 방에 대해…
...about the Chamber of Secrets?
뭔가 알고 있나요?
그래
Can you...
나한테…
...tell me?
말해 줄 수 있어요?
아니
하지만 보여 줄 순 있어
50년 전으로 데려가 줄게
6월 13일
Excuse me. Could you tell
me what's going on here?
죄송하지만, 지금
무슨 일이 벌어지는 거죠?
Are you Tom Riddle?
당신이 톰 리들이에요?
Hello, can you hear me?
내 말 들려요?
Riddle!
리들!
Come.
이리 오거라
Professor Dumbledore.
덤블도어 교수님
Dumbledore?
덤블도어 교수님?
It is not wise to be wandering
around this late hour, Tom.
이런 늦은 시간에
돌아다니면 안 된다, 톰
Yes, Professor. I suppose I...
네, 교수님
저는 다만…
I had to see for myself
if the rumors were true.
소문이 사실인지
직접 확인하고 싶어서요
I'm afraid they are, Tom.
They are true.
그래, 톰
유감이지만 사실이다
About the school as well? I
don't have a home to go to.
학교 얘기도요?
전 돌아갈 집도 없어요
They wouldn't really close
Hogwarts, would they, Professor?
정말 호그와트가
문을 닫는 건 아니죠?
I understand, Tom,
but I'm afraid...
나도 이해한다만
안타깝게도
...Headmaster Dippet
may have no choice.
디펫 교장 선생님도
어쩔 도리가 없으시단다
Sir, if it all stopped, if the
person responsible was caught...
선생님, 만일 그 짓을 한 자가
잡히고 공격이 멈춘다면…
Is there something...
혹시 나한테
...you wish to tell me?
뭔가 할 말이 있느냐?
No, sir. Nothing.
아뇨, 없습니다
Very well, then. Off you go.
그렇다면 좋다
그만 가 보거라
Good night, sir.
안녕히 주무세요
- Let's get you out of there.
- Evening, Hagrid.
- 내가 여기서 꺼내 줄게
- 해그리드
I'm going to have to turn you in. I don't
think you meant it to kill anyone...
너를 고발해야겠어
누굴 죽이려 한 건 아니겠지만…
You can't. You don't understand.
안돼! 넌 이해 못 해
The dead girl's parents will be here
tomorrow. The least Hogwarts can do...
죽은 여학생의 부모가
내일 여기 올 텐데 학교에서
...is make sure the thing that killed
their daughter is slaughtered.
최소한 그 애를 죽인
괴물이라도 처치해야지
It wasn't him. Aragog never
killed no one. Never.
아냐, 아라고그는 아무도
죽이지 않았어
Monsters don't make
good pets, Hagrid.
괴물은 애완동물이
될 수 없어, 해그리드
- Now, stand aside.
- No!
- 비켜
- 안돼!
- Stand aside, Hagrid.
- No!
- 어서, 해그리드
- 안 된다니까!
Cistem Aperio!
시스템 아페리오!
Arania Exumai!
아라니아 엑수메이!
Aragog!
아라고그!
I can't let you go.
못 보내 줘
They'll have your wand for this,
Hagrid. You'll be expelled.
넌 요술 지팡이를 뺏기고
퇴학당할 거야
Hagrid!
해그리드 아저씨!
It was Hagrid. Hagrid opened the
Chamber of Secrets 50 years ago.
해그리드야, 해그리드 아저씨가
50년 전에 비밀의 방을 열었어
It can't be Hagrid.
It just can't be.
그럴 리가 없어
말도 안 돼
We don't even know this Tom Riddle. He
sounds like a dirty, rotten snitch.
톰 리들이 누군지도 모르잖아
치사한 고자질장이처럼 들리는데
The monster had killed somebody,
Ron. What would any of us have done?
괴물이 사람을 죽였어
우리라면 어떻게 했겠어?
Look, Hagrid's our friend. Why don't
we just go and ask him about it?
아저씨는 우리 친구니까
가서 직접 물어보자
That would be a cheerful visit.
"Hello, Hagrid.
참 좋아하겠다
"안녕하세요, 아저씨"
Tell us, have you been setting anything mad
and hairy loose in the castle lately?"
"최근에 미친 털투성이 괴물을
성에 풀었나요?"
Mad and hairy? You wouldn't be
talking about me, now, would you?
미친 털투성이?
설마 내 얘기는 아니겠지?
No.
아뇨!
What's that you've got, Hagrid?
그게 뭐예요?
It's Flesh-Eating Slug Repellent.
For the Mandrakes, you know.
맨드레이크에 쓸
육식성 민달팽이 살충제야
Now, according to Professor Sprout,
they've still got a bit of growing to do.
스프라우트 교수님 말씀이
아직 좀 더 자라야 한다는구나
But once their acne's cleared up,
we'll chop them up and stew them...
맨드레이크의 여드름이 없어지면
썰고 달여서
...and then we'll get those people
down at the hospital un-Petrified.
병원에 있는 마비된 사람들을
고칠 수 있을 거야
In the meantime,
though, you three...
그동안 너희 셋은
...had best be looking after
yourselves. All right?
서로 잘 지켜 주거라, 알았지?
Hello, Neville.
안녕, 네빌
Harry, I don't know who did
it, but you'd better come.
해리, 누구 짓인지는 몰라도
어서 와 봐
Come on!
서둘러!
It had to be a Gryffindor.
Nobody else knows our password.
그리핀도르 학생일 거야
다른 사람은 우리 암호를 모르잖아
Unless it wasn't a student.
하지만 학생이
아닐 수도 있지
Whoever it was, they must have
been looking for something.
누구였든간에
뭔가 찾으러 온 게 분명해
And they found it.
그리고 찾았어
Tom Riddle's diary is gone.
톰 리들의 일기가 사라졌어
All right, listen up.
잘 들어
We play our game, Hufflepuff
doesn't stand a chance.
우리가 제대로 하면
후플푸프는 상대가 안 돼
We're stronger,
quicker and smarter.
힘, 속도, 지능
우리가 한 수 위야
Not to mention they're dead scared
that Harry will Petrify them...
또 해리가 돌처럼 굳게
만들까 봐 무서워서
...if they fly anywhere
near him. - Well, that too.
- 해리 주변엔 얼씬도 못 할 거야
- 그것도 그렇지
Professor McGonagall.
맥고나걸 교수님
- This match has been canceled.
- We can't cancel Quidditch.
- 시합은 취소됐다
- 퀴디치를 취소하다뇨!
Silence, Wood. You and your teammates
will go to Gryffindor Tower. Now.
조용히 해라, 모두들
그리핀도르 탑으로 가, 당장
Potter, you and I will
find Mr. Weasley.
포터, 넌 나랑
위즐리를 찾으러 가자
There's something the
both of you have to see.
너희 둘이 봐야 할 게 있단다
I warn you. This could
be a wee bit of a shock.
미리 말해 두지만
좀 놀랄 수도 있을 거다
Hermione!
헤르미온느!
She was found near
the library...
도서관 근처에서 발견됐어
...along with this.
이것과 함께
Does it mean anything
to either of you?
뭔가 짚이는 거 없니?
No.
없어요
Could I have your
attention, please?
모두들 주목해 주세요
Because of recent events, these new rules
will be put into effect immediately.
최근의 사건들 때문에
새 규칙을 바로 시행하겠어요
"All students will return to their house
common rooms by 6:00 every evening."
"모든 학생은 매일 저녁 6시까지
기숙사 휴게실로 돌아간다"
All students will be escorted
to each lesson by a teacher.
"모든 학생은 모든 수업마다
교수의 동반 하에 교실로 간다"
"No exceptions."
"예외는 없다"
I should tell you this.
이 얘기는 해야겠구나
Unless the culprit behind
these attacks is caught...
이 공격 사건의 배후에 있는
범인이 잡히지 않으면
...it is likely the
school will be closed.
학교 문을
닫게 될 가능성이 높다
We've got to talk to Hagrid,
Ron. I can't believe it's him...
해그리드와 얘기해야 돼
나도 믿기지는 않지만
...but if he did set the
monster loose last time...
지난번에 아저씨가
괴물을 풀어 줬다면
...he'll know how to get inside the
Chamber of Secrets. That's a start.
비밀의 방에 들어가는
방법을 알 거야
But you heard McGonagall.
교수님 말씀 못 들었어?
We're not allowed to leave
the tower except for class.
수업 시간 말고는
탑에서 나갈 수 없어
I think it's time to get my
dad's old cloak out again.
우리 아빠의 망토를 쓸 때가
또 온 것 같아
Who's there?
거기 누구요?
Hello?
이봐요
누구요?
- What's that for?
- Nothing. I was expecting...
- 그건 뭐에 쓰려고요?
- 아무것도 아냐, 혹시…
It doesn't matter. Come on in.
I just made a pot of tea.
그건 됐고, 들어오렴
방금 차를 끓였어
Hagrid, are you okay?
해그리드 아저씨, 괜찮아요?
I'm fine. I'm all right.
괜찮아
아무 문제 없다
Did you hear about Hermione?
헤르미온느 얘기 들었어요?
Yeah. I heard about
that, all right.
그래, 나도 들었어
Look, we have to
ask you something.
저기, 물어볼 게 있어요
Do you know who's opened
the Chamber of Secrets?
누가 비밀의 방을
열었는지 아세요?
What you had to understand
about that is...
너희들이 꼭
알아야 하는 건…
Quick, under the cloak.
빨리 망토 안에 숨어라
Don't say a word. Be
quiet, both of you.
둘 다 아무 말 말고
잠자코 있어
- Professor Dumbledore, sir.
- Good evening, Hagrid.
- 덤블도어 교수님
- 안녕한가, 해그리드
I wonder, could we...?
들어가도 괜찮겠나?
Of course. Come in. Come in.
그럼요, 들어오세요
That's Dad's boss.
아빠의 상관이야
Cornelius Fudge,
Minister of Magic.
마법부 장관
코넬리우스 퍼지야
Bad business, Hagrid, very
bad business. Had to come.
매우 안 좋은 일이네, 해그리드
올 수밖에 없었어
Three attacks on Muggle-borns.
Things have gone far enough.
세 명의 머글 태생이 당했네
이건 너무 지나쳤어
- The Ministry's got to act.
- But I never...
- 마법부는 조치를 취해야 돼
- 하지만 전 아니에요…
You know I never, Professor.
교수님은 아시잖아요
I want it understood,
Cornelius...
이건 알아주십시오
코넬리우스
...that Hagrid...
전 해그리드를
...has my full confidence.
굳게 믿습니다
Albus, look, Hagrid's
record is against him.
해그리드는 전과가 있잖소
- I've got to take him.
- Take me?
- 데려가야 돼요
- 저를 데려가요?
Take me where? Not
Azkaban prison.
어디로요?
아즈카반 감옥은 아니겠죠?
I'm afraid we have
no choice, Hagrid.
어쩔 수가 없네, 해그리드
Already here, Fudge?
벌써 오셨군요, 장관님
Good.
잘됐네요
What are you doing here?
Get out of my house!
댁이 여긴 웬일이슈?
내 집에서 나가요!
Believe me...
물론이지
...I take absolutely no
pleasure being inside your...
나도 자네 집에 발을
들여놓고 싶어서 온 게 아냐
You call this a house?
이걸 집이라고 하나?
No.
아닐세
I simply called up the school and
was told the headmaster was here.
학교에 연락했더니
교장님이 여기 계신다고 해서 왔지
Well, what exactly is it
that you want with me?
나한테 용건이 뭡니까?
The other governors and I have decided
it's time for you to step aside.
저와 다른 이사진은 교장님이
물러날 때라는 결론을 내렸습니다
This is an order of suspension.
정직 명령서입니다
You'll find all 12
signatures on it.
12명 모두 서명했습니다
I'm afraid we feel you've
rather lost your touch.
교장님 실력이 예전 같지
않으시다고 느껴서요
Well, what, with all
these attacks...
이번 사건만 해도 그래요
...there'll be no Muggle-borns
left at Hogwarts.
이러다 호그와트에
머글 태생이 남아나질 않겠군요
I can only imagine what an awful
loss that would be to the school.
그렇게 되면 학교에 손실이
이만저만이 아니겠죠
You can't take Professor
Dumbledore away.
덤블도어 교수님을
데려갈 순 없어요
Take him away and the Muggle-borns
won't stand a chance.
교수님이 안 계시면
머글 태생은 설 자리가 없어요
You mark my words,
there'll be killings next!
다음엔 누가 죽게 될 거요!
You think so?
그렇게 생각하나?
Calm yourself, Hagrid.
진정하게, 해그리드
If the governors
desire my removal...
이사들이 내가
그만두기를 원한다면
...I will, of
course, step aside.
두말없이 물러나야지
However...
허나 알아 두시오
...you will find that help will
always be given at Hogwarts...
호그와트에서는 언제나
도움을 원하는 사람에게
...to those who...
도움의 손길이
...ask for it.
와 닿게 되어 있습니다
Admirable sentiments.
멋진 말씀이군요
Shall we?
가실까요?
Fudge.
퍼지
Come, Hagrid.
가세, 해그리드
Well?
어서
If...
만약에…
If anybody was looking
for some stuff...
누가 뭔가를 찾고 있다면
...then all they'd have to do
would be to follow the spiders.
거미들만 따라가면
찾을 수 있을 겁니다
Yep. That would lead them right.
네, 올바른 곳으로
인도해 줄 거예요
That's all I have to say.
더 이상 할 말 없습니다
And someone will need to
feed Fang while I'm away.
그리고 제가 없는 동안
누가 팽의 먹이를 줘야 해요
Good boy.
착하지
Hagrid's right.
해그리드 아저씨 말이 맞아
With Dumbledore gone,
there'll be an attack a day.
덤블도어 교수님이 없으면
매일 습격이 계속될 거야
Look.
저것 봐
Come on.
가자
Come on, Fang.
팽, 너도 가자
Come on.
가자
What?
뭐?
You heard what Hagrid said.
"Follow the spiders."
아저씨 말 못 들었어?
"거미를 따라가라"
They're heading to
the Dark Forest.
어둠의 숲으로 가고 있잖아
Why spiders? Why couldn't it
be "follow the butterflies"?
왜 하필 거미야?
나비를 따라가라고 하지
Harry, I don't like this.
해리, 난 기분이 안 내켜
- Harry, I don't like
this at all. - Shush!
- 전혀 안 내킨다고
- 쉿!
Can we go back now?
이제 돌아가면 안 될까?
Come on.
빨리 와
Who is it?
거기 누구냐?
Don't panic.
당황하지 마
Hagrid?
해그리드?
Is that you?
해그리드야?
We're friends of Hagrid's.
저희는 해그리드의 친구예요
And you? You're
Aragog, aren't you?
당신은요?
아라고그 맞죠?
Yes.
그렇다
Hagrid has never sent men
into our hollow before.
해그리드는 내가 있는 곳으로
사람을 보낸 적이 없는데
He's in trouble. Up at the
school, there have been attacks.
아저씨가 곤경에 처했어요
학교에서 누가 공격당했는데
They think it's Hagrid.
사람들은
아저씨 짓인 줄 알아요
They think he opened the Chamber
of Secrets. Like before.
예전처럼 비밀의 방을
열었다고 생각한다고요
That's a lie.
그건 거짓말이야!
Hagrid never opened the
Chamber of Secrets.
해그리드는 비밀의 방을
연 적이 없어
- Then you're not the monster?
- No.
- 그럼 당신은 그 괴물이 아닌가요?
- 아냐
The monster was
born in the castle.
그 괴물은 성에서 태어났어
I came to Hagrid from a distant
land in the pocket of a traveler.
난 먼 곳에서부터 여행자의
주머니에 숨어서 해그리드에게 온 거야
Harry.
해리
But if you're not the monster, then
what did kill that girl 50 years ago?
당신이 그 괴물이 아니라면
누가 50년 전에 그 소녀를 죽였죠?
We do not speak of it.
우린 그 얘기는
하지 않는다
It is an ancient creature we
spiders fear above all others.
우리 거미들이 가장 두려워하는
고대의 생물이야
But have you seen it?
본 적은 있어요?
I never saw any part of the castle
but the box in which Hagrid kept me.
해그리드가 날 넣어 둔 상자 말고는
아무것도 못 봤다
The girl was discovered
in a bathroom.
그 소녀는 화장실에서 발견됐다
When I was accused,
Hagrid brought me here.
내가 누명을 뒤집어쓰자
해그리드가 날 여기로 데려왔지
- Harry!
- What?
- 해리!
- 왜?
Well, thank you.
네, 고맙습니다
We'll just go.
그럼 저희는 가 볼게요
Go?
간다고?
I think not.
그렇게는 안 되지
My sons and daughters do not
harm Hagrid on my command.
내 명령에 따라 내 자식들은
해그리드를 해치지 않는다
But I cannot deny
them fresh meat...
하지만 자진해서
우리에게 온
...when it wanders so
willingly into our midst.
신선한 고기를
마다할 수는 없지
Goodbye, friend of Hagrid.
잘 가거라
해그리드의 친구들아
Can we panic now?
이제 당황해도 돼?
Know any spells?
주문 아는 거 없어?
One, but it's not powerful
enough for all of them.
하나 있는데
전부 다 처치하기엔 무리야
Where's Hermione
when you need her?
헤르미온느는 필요할 때
어디 있는 거야?
Let's go!
가자!
Arania Exumai!
아라니아 엑수메이!
Go!
가자!
Glad we're out of there.
다행히 빠져나왔어
Arania Exumai!
아라니아 엑수메이!
- Thanks for that.
- Don't mention it.
- 고마워
- 천만에
Get us out of here.
여기서 나가자
Now!
당장!
Come on! Come on, move faster!
어서! 더 빨리 가!
Come on! Go!
어서! 서둘러!
Get us in the air.
하늘로 날아!
The flying gear's jammed!
비행 기어가 안 움직여!
- Come on! Pull!
- I'm trying!
- 어서, 당겨!
- 하고 있어!
Follow the spiders.
거미를 따라가라
If Hagrid ever gets out of
Azkaban, I'll kill him.
아저씨가 아즈카반에서 나오면
내가 죽일 거야
I mean, what was the point
of sending us in there?
우릴 거기로 보낸 이유가 뭐야?
- What have we found out?
- We know one thing.
- 우리가 뭘 알아냈냐고?
- 한 가지는 알았잖아
Hagrid never opened the
Chamber of Secrets.
아저씨는 비밀의 방을
연 적이 없어
He was innocent.
아저씨는 결백했어
Wish you were here, Hermione.
네가 여기 있으면 좋겠어
헤르미온느
We need you.
네가 필요해
Now more than ever.
그 어느 때보다도 지금 더
- What's that?
- Ron...
- 그게 뭐야?
- 론
This is why Hermione was in the
library the day she was attacked.
이것 때문에 헤르미온느가 공격당하던 날
도서관에 있었던 거야
Come on.
가자!
"Of the many fearsome beasts
that roam our land..."
"우리의 땅을 방황하는
수많은 맹수들 중에"
...none is more deadly than the basilisk.
Capable of living for hundreds of years...
"가장 무서운 것은 바실리스크다
이것은 수백 년간 살 수 있으며"
...instant death awaits any who
meet this giant serpent's eye.
"이 거대한 독사의 눈을
보는 사람은 즉시 죽는다"
"Spiders flee before
it." Ron, this is it.
"거미들은 그의 앞에서 달아난다"
론, 이거야
The monster in the Chamber
of Secrets is a basilisk.
비밀의 방에 있는 괴물은
바실리스크야
That's why I can hear it speak.
It's a snake.
그래서 내가 그 목소리를
들은 거야, 뱀이니까
But if it kills by looking people in
the eye, why is it no one's dead?
눈을 보면 죽는다면서
왜 아무도 안 죽었지?
Because no one did
look it in the eye.
눈을 본 사람은 없으니까
Not directly, at least.
적어도 직접 보진 않았어
Colin saw it through his camera.
콜린은
카메라를 통해서 봤어
Justin... Justin must have seen the
basilisk through Nearly Headless Nick.
저스틴은 목이 달랑달랑한
닉을 통해 봤을 거야
Nick got the full blast of it. But
he's a ghost, he couldn't die again.
닉은 제대로 봤지만 유령이라서
또 죽을 수는 없잖아
And Hermione had the mirror.
헤르미온느는
거울을 갖고 있었어
I bet you she was using it to look
around corners in case it came along.
그게 나타날 경우를 대비해
모퉁이를 거울로 비춰 본 거야
And Mrs. Norris?
노리스 부인은?
I'm pretty sure she didn't have
a camera or a mirror, Harry.
카메라나 거울 따위
안 갖고 있었을 거 아냐
The water.
물이야
There was water on the floor that night.
She only saw the basilisk's reflection.
그날 밤 바닥에 물이 고여 있었어
물에 비친 것만 본 거지
"Spiders flee before it."
"거미들은 그의 앞에서 달아난다"
- It all fits. - How's a
basilisk been getting around?
- 다 맞아 떨어져!
- 근데 어떻게 돌아다니고 있지?
A dirty, great snake.
Someone would have seen it.
더럽고 큰 뱀이잖아
누군가 봤을 텐데
- Hermione's answered that too. -
Pipes? It's using the plumbing.
- 헤르미온느가 그것도 대답했어
- 배수관? 그 안으로 다녔군
Remember what Aragog said
about that girl 50 years ago?
50년 전의 소녀에 대해
아라고그가 한 말 기억나?
She died in a bathroom?
What if she never left?
화장실에서 죽었다고 했지?
여전히 여기 남아 있다면?
Moaning Myrtle.
모우닝 머틀!
All students are to return to
their house dormitories at once.
학생들은 즉시
기숙사로 돌아가세요
All teachers to the second-floor
corridor immediately.
선생님들은 모두
2층 복도로 와 주세요
As you can see, the Heir of
Slytherin has left another message.
슬리데린의 후계자가
또 다른 메시지를 남겼어요
Our worst fear has
been realized.
가장 우려했던 것이
현실로 나타났어요
A student has been taken by the
monster into the Chamber itself.
괴물이 한 학생을
비밀의 방으로 끌고 갔어요
The students must be sent home. I'm
afraid this is the end of Hogwarts.
학생들을 집으로 보내야 해요
이제 호그와트도 끝이군요
So sorry. Dozed off.
What have I missed?
죄송해요, 잠시 졸았습니다
무슨 일이죠?
A girl has been snatched by the monster,
Lockhart. Your moment has come at last.
괴물이 여학생을 납치했소
드디어 당신의 때가 왔군요
- My moment? - Weren't you
saying just last night...
- 나의 때라고요?
- 어젯밤에 그러셨잖소
...that you've known all along where the
entrance to the Chamber of Secrets is?
당신은 비밀의 방으로 가는 길을
항상 알고 있었다고
That's settled. We'll leave you to
deal with the monster, Gilderoy.
그럼 괴물은 선생님이
처리하면 되겠군요
- Your skills, after all,
are legend. - Very well.
- 마법 실력도 전설적이시잖아요
- 알겠습니다
I'll just be in my
office getting...
그럼 제 방으로 가서…
Getting ready.
준비를 하죠
Who is it that the
monster's taken, Minerva?
괴물이 누구를 데려갔죠?
Ginny Weasley.
지니 위즐리요
"Her skeleton will lie
in the Chamber forever."
"그녀의 뼈는 영원히
비밀의 방에 묻힐 것이다"
Ginny.
지니
Lockhart may be useless, but he's going
to try and get into the Chamber.
록허트 교수님은 실력은 없지만
비밀의 방에 들어가려 할 거야
At least we can tell
him what we know.
우리가 아는 거라도
말씀드리자
Professor, we have some
information for you.
교수님, 말씀드릴 게 있어요
Are you going somewhere?
어디 가세요?
Well, yes. Urgent call.
Unavoidable. Got to go.
그래, 급한 전갈이 와서
가 봐야 한단다
- What about my sister?
- Well...
- 제 동생은 어떡하고요?
- 그게…
As to that, most unfortunate.
No one regrets more than I.
그 일은 정말 안 됐다
나도 정말 안타깝구나
You're the Defense Against the Dark
Arts teacher. You can't go now.
어둠의 마법 방어술 교수님이
지금 가시면 어떡해요?
I must say, when I took the job, there
was nothing in the description...
내가 이 자리를 맡기로 했을 때
이런 말은 없었…
You're running away?
도망치시는 거예요?
- After all you did in your
books? - Books can be misleading.
- 책에 나온 얘기는 다 뭐죠?
- 책은 오해를 낳기도 해
- You wrote them. - My dear
boy, use your common sense.
- 직접 쓰셨잖아요
- 상식적으로 생각하렴
My books wouldn't have sold as well if
people didn't think I'd done those things.
내가 그런 일을 했다고 해야
사람들이 책을 많이 사지
You're a fraud.
교수님은 사기꾼이에요
You've been taking credit for
what other wizards have done.
다른 마법사들의 공로를
가로챘어요
Is there anything you can do?
할 줄 아는 게
있긴 하세요?
Yes, now you mention it. I'm
rather gifted with Memory Charms.
말이 나왔으니 말인데
내가 기억력 마술은 꽤 잘하지
Otherwise, all those wizards
would have gone blabbing.
그게 아니면 다른 마법사들의
기억을 못 지웠을 거야
I'd never have
sold another book.
책도 못 팔았겠지
In fact, I'm going to have
to do the same to you.
사실, 너희들에게도
똑같이 해야겠구나
Don't even think about it.
꿈 깨세요!
Who's there?
누구야?
Hello, Harry.
안녕, 해리
- What do you want?
- To ask you how you died.
- 왜 왔어?
- 네가 어떻게 죽었는지 물어보려고
It was dreadful.
끔찍했어
It happened right here
in this very cubicle.
바로 이 칸막이 안에서
벌어졌어
I'd hidden because Olive Hornby
was teasing me about my glasses.
올리브가 내 안경을 놀리길래
여기 숨었어
I was crying, and then I
heard somebody come in.
울고 있는데
누가 들어오는 소리가 들렸지
- Who was it, Myrtle? - I
don't know. I was distraught!
- 그게 누구였는데?
- 몰라, 너무 속상했단 말이야!
But they said something funny,
a kind of made-up language.
근데 이상한 말을 했어
만들어 낸 말 같더라
And I realized it was a boy, so I unlocked
the door to tell him to go away and...
남자애인 걸 알고
꺼지라고 하려고 문을 열었는데…
- ...I died.
- Just like that? How?
- 죽고 말았어
- 그냥 그렇게? 어떻게?
I just remember seeing a pair
of great, big, yellow eyes...
커다랗고 노란 눈 두 개를
본 게 기억나
...over there by that sink.
저 세면대 옆에서
This is it.
바로 이거야
This is it, Ron. I think this is the
entrance to the Chamber of Secrets.
론, 여기가 비밀의 방의
입구인 것 같아
Say something. Harry, say
something in Parseltongue.
뭐라고 말해 봐, 해리
뱀의 말로 뭐라고 해봐
Excellent, Harry. Good work.
Well, then, I'll just be...
해리, 아주 잘했다
그럼 난…
There's no need for me to stay.
여기 없어도 되겠구나!
Yes, there is.
가긴 어딜 가요!
- You first. - Now, boys,
what good will it do?
- 먼저 가세요
- 그런다고 뭐가 좋겠어?
Better you than us.
우리보단 낫겠죠
But... Obviously, yes.
뭐, 그건 맞는 말이야
Sure you don't want
to test it first?
정말 너희들이 먼저
안 가 볼래?
It's really quite
filthy down here.
여긴 꽤 더럽구나
- All right. Let's go.
- Oh, Harry?
- 좋아, 가자
- 해리?
If you die down there, you're
welcome to share my toilet.
만약 거기서 죽으면
나랑 여기서 같이 지내도 좋아
Thanks, Myrtle.
고마워, 머틀
Now, remember: Any sign of movement,
close your eyes straightaway.
잊지 마, 무슨 기척이 있으면
바로 눈을 감아
Go on.
가요
This way.
이쪽이야
- What's this?
- It looks like a snake.
- 이게 뭐지?
- 뱀 같이 생겼는데
- It's a snakeskin.
- Bloody hell.
- 뱀 허물이야
- 세상에!
Whatever shed this must
be 60 feet long. Or more.
이걸 벗었다면
20미터는 족히 되겠어
Heart of a lion, this one.
아주 용감한 분이시네
The adventure ends here, boys.
But don't fret.
모험은 여기서 끝이다
하지만 걱정 마라
The world will know our story. How
I was too late to save the girl.
세상에 우리 얘기를 알리마
내가 소녀를 구하기엔 너무 늦었고
How you two tragically
lost your minds...
너희들은 엉망이 된
소녀의 시체를 보고
...at the sight of
her mangled body.
불쌍하게도
정신이 나가 버렸다고
So...
자…
You first, Mr. Potter.
너부터다, 포터 군
Say goodbye to your memories.
이제 네 기억과
작별 인사를 하렴
Obliviate!
오블리비아테!
해리!
- Ron! Ron, are you okay?
- I'm fine.
- 론! 론, 괜찮아?
- 난 괜찮아
Hello.
안녕
Who are you?
넌 누구니?
- Ron Weasley.
- Really?
- 론 위즐리요
- 그래?
And who am I?
그럼 난 누구지?
Lockhart's Memory Charm backfired.
He hasn't got a clue who he is.
기억력 마술이 거꾸로 먹혔어
자기가 누구인지도 몰라!
It's an odd sort of
place, isn't it?
여기는 참 이상한 곳이구나
안 그러니?
Do you live here?
너 여기 사니?
- No.
- Really?
- 아뇨
- 정말?
- What do I do now?
- You wait here...
- 이제 어떡하지?
- 여기서 기다려
...and try and shift some of this
rock so we can get back through.
이 돌 좀 치워 둬
나중에 돌아갈 수 있게
- I'll go on and find Ginny.
- Okay.
- 난 가서 지니를 찾을게
- 알았어
지니
Ginny! Ginny, please don't
be dead. Wake up, wake up.
지니! 죽으면 안 돼
정신 차려!
Please wake up.
제발 눈을 떠
She won't wake.
못 깰 거야
Tom. Tom Riddle. What do
you mean, she won't wake?
톰! 톰 리들
못 깬다니 무슨 말이에요?
- She's not...? - She's
still alive, but only just.
- 설마…
- 아직 살아 있지만 얼마 못 버텨
- Are you a ghost?
- A memory...
- 당신은 유령인가요?
- 나는 기억이야
...preserved in a
diary for 50 years.
50년간 일기장 속에
보존되어 있었지
She's cold as ice. Ginny,
please don't be dead. Wake up.
몸이 얼음장 같아, 지니
죽으면 안 돼, 눈을 떠
You've got to help me, Tom.
There's a basilisk.
날 도와줘요, 톰
바실리스크가 있어요
It won't come until it's called.
불러내기 전엔 안 나와
- Give me my wand, Tom.
- You won't be needing it.
- 제 지팡이 주세요
- 넌 필요 없을 거야
- We've got to go. We've got to save
her. - I'm afraid I can't do that.
- 가야죠, 지니를 살려야 해요
- 그렇겐 못 해
You see, as poor Ginny grows
weaker, I grow stronger.
지니가 약해질수록
내가 강해지거든
Yes, Harry, it was Ginny Weasley
who opened the Chamber of Secrets.
그래, 지니 위즐리가
비밀의 방의 문을 열었어
No. She couldn't. She wouldn't.
아뇨, 그렇지 않아요
지니가 그럴 리 없어요
It was Ginny who set the basilisk
on the Mudbloods and Filch's cat...
바실리스크를 풀어서 잡종들과
필치의 고양이를 공격하고
...Ginny who wrote the threatening
messages on the walls.
벽에 협박문을 쓴 건
모두 지니 짓이야
- But why?
- Because I told her to.
- 왜죠?
- 내가 시켰거든
You'll find I can be very persuasive.
Not that she knew what she was doing.
내가 설득을 잘하거든
지니는 자기가 뭘 하는지도 몰랐지
She was, shall we say,
in a kind of trance.
말하자면
최면 상태였다고나 할까?
Still, the power of the
diary began to scare her.
하지만 일기의 힘을
두려워하기 시작했고
She tried to dispose of it
in the girls' bathroom.
여자 화장실에서
그걸 없애려고 했지
And then who should
find it but you?
그런데 그걸 바로
네가 찾아낸 거지
The very person I was
most anxious to meet.
내가 만나기를 갈망하던
사람 말이야
And why did you want to meet me?
왜 날 만나고 싶어 했죠?
I knew I had to talk to
you, meet you if I could.
할 수 있다면 너와 만나서
얘기를 해야 했거든
So I decided to show you my capture
of that brainless oaf Hagrid...
난 네 신뢰를 얻기 위해
멍청이 해그리드를
- ...to gain your trust.
- Hagrid's my friend.
- 잡는 장면을 보여 줬지
- 아저씨는 내 친구예요!
- And you framed him, didn't you? -
It was my word against Hagrid's.
- 당신이 누명을 씌웠죠?
- 사람들은 내 말을 믿었지
Only Dumbledore seemed to
think he was innocent.
덤블도어만 그가 결백하다고
생각하는 것 같더군
I'll bet Dumbledore saw
right through you.
교수님은 당신을
제대로 꿰뚫어 봤겠죠
He certainly kept an annoyingly
close watch on me after that.
확실히 그 뒤로 성가시게
날 감시하긴 했지
I knew it wouldn't be safe to open the
Chamber again while I was at school...
내가 학교에 있는 한 비밀의 방을
여는 건 안전하지 않겠더군
...so I decided to leave
behind a diary...
그래서 16살의 나를
...preserving my 16-year-old
self in its pages...
일기장에 보존하기로 했지
...so that one day I would
be able to lead another...
언젠가는 다른 사람을
유도해서
...to finish Salazar
Slytherin's noble work.
살라자르 슬리데린의
고귀한 업적을 완성케 하려고!
Well, you haven't
finished it this time.
이번엔 완성하지 못할걸
In a few hours, the Mandrake
Draught will be ready.
몇 시간 뒤면
맨드레이크 회복약이 준비돼
And everyone who was Petrified
will be all right again.
그럼 마비됐던 사람들은
모두 정상이 될 거야
Haven't I told you? Killing Mudbloods
doesn't matter to me anymore.
내가 말 안 했나? 잡종을 죽이는 건
이제 내겐 아무 의미도 없어
For many months now, my
new target has been you.
몇 달 동안
내 새로운 목표는 너였어
How is it that a baby with no
extraordinary magical talent...
특별한 마법의 재능도 없는
애송이가
...was able to defeat the
greatest wizard of all time?
어떻게 역사상 가장 위대한
마법사를 이겼지?
How did you escape with
nothing but a scar...
마왕 볼드모트의 힘은
파괴되고 말았는데
...while Lord Voldemort's
powers were destroyed?
넌 어떻게 상처만 입고
도망칠 수 있었지?
Why do you care how I escaped?
Voldemort was after your time.
당신이 무슨 상관이지?
볼드모트는 당신 이후의 사람인데
Voldemort is my past,
present and future.
볼드모트는 내 과거이자
현재이고 미래야
톰 마볼로 리들
나는 마왕 볼드모트다
You. You're the
Heir of Slytherin.
당신이 슬리데린의
후계자군
- You're Voldemort.
- Surely you didn't think...
- 당신이 볼드모트야
- 설마 내가 더러운
...I was going to keep my
filthy Muggle father's name?
머글 아버지의 성을
따랐을 거라 생각했나?
No. I fashioned myself a new name, a
name I knew wizards everywhere...
아니지, 내가 세상에서
가장 위대한 마법사가 됐을 때
...would fear to speak when I became
the greatest sorcerer in the world.
사람들이 입에 올리기도 두려워할
새 이름을 지었어
Albus Dumbledore is the
greatest sorcerer in the world.
알버스 덤블도어가
세상에서 제일 위대한 마법사야!
Dumbledore's been driven out of this
castle by the mere memory of me.
덤블도어는 고작 나의 기억 때문에
성에서 추방당했어
He'll never be gone. Not as long as
those who remain are loyal to him.
남은 사람들이 덤블도어에게
충성하는 한 그런 일은 없어
Fawkes?
퍽스?
So this is what Dumbledore
sends his great defender.
이게 덤블도어가 자신을
옹호하는 자에게 보내는 선물이군
A songbird and an old hat.
우는 새와
낡은 모자라니
Let's match the power of Lord
Voldemort, Heir of Salazar Slytherin...
살라자르 슬리데린의 후계자인
마왕 볼드모트의 힘과
...against the
famous Harry Potter.
유명하신 해리 포터의
힘의 대결을 펼쳐 볼까?
Parseltongue won't save you
now, Potter. It only obeys me.
뱀의 말은 널 살리지 못해
이놈은 내 말만 따른다
No!
안돼!
Your bird may have blinded the
basilisk, but it can still hear you.
네 새가 눈은 멀게 했지만
아직 소리는 들을 수 있어
Yes, Potter. The process
is nearly complete.
그래, 포터
이제 거의 다 완성됐어
In a few minutes, Ginny Weasley will be
dead, and I will cease to be a memory.
몇 분 뒤면 지니 위즐리는 죽고
난 더 이상 기억이 아니게 되겠지
Lord Voldemort will return...
마왕 볼드모트가
돌아오는 거야
...very much alive.
생생하게 살아서 말이야
Ginny?
지니?
Remarkable, isn't it...
놀랍지?
...how quickly the venom of the
basilisk penetrates the body?
바실리스크의 독이
그렇게 빨리 퍼진다니 말이야
I'd guess you have little
more than a minute to live.
1분 정도면
네 목숨도 끝일 거다
You'll be with your dear
Mudblood mother soon, Harry.
곧 네 잡종 어머니를
만날 수 있을 거다, 해리
Funny, the damage a silly
little book can do...
재미있군
이런 바보 같은 책이
...especially in the hands
of a silly little girl.
바보 같은 여자애의 손에서
이런 힘을 발휘하다니
What are you doing?
뭐하는 거야?
Stop. No!
멈춰, 안돼!
지니
It was me. But I swear,
I didn't mean to.
내가 그랬어, 하지만
그러려고 했던 건 아니야
Riddle made me, and...
리들이 시켰어, 그래서…
Harry, you're hurt.
해리, 다쳤잖아
Don't worry.
걱정 마
Ginny, you need to
get yourself out.
지니, 넌 여기서 나가
Follow the Chamber
and you'll find Ron.
방을 따라 나가면
론이 있을 거야
You were brilliant, Fawkes.
넌 훌륭했어, 퍽스
I just wasn't quick enough.
그냥 내가 느렸던 거야
Of course.
맞아!
Phoenix tears have
healing powers.
불사조의 눈물에는
치유력이 있지
Thanks.
고마워
It's all right, Ginny.
괜찮아, 지니
It's over.
다 끝났어
It's just a memory.
이젠 단지 기억일 뿐이야
Amazing! This is
just like magic!
굉장하구나!
이거 꼭 마법 같다!
You both realize, of course...
둘 다 알고 있겠지
...that in the past few hours, you have
broken perhaps a dozen school rules.
너희들이 지난 몇 시간 동안 교칙을
열 개도 넘게 어겼다는 걸
Yes, sir.
네, 교수님
There is sufficient evidence
to have you both expelled.
둘 다 퇴학시킬 이유가 충분해
Yes, sir.
- 네
Therefore, it is only fitting...
그러므로 너희 둘은
...that you both receive...
학교를 위해
...Special Awards for
Services to the School.
봉사한 것에 대한
특별상을 받아 마땅하다
Thanks, sir.
고맙습니다
Now, Mr. Weasley,
if you would...
위즐리 군, 부엉이를 시켜서
...have an owl deliver these
release papers to Azkaban.
이 석방 명령문을
아즈카반으로 보내라
I believe we want our
gamekeeper back.
우리 관리인을
다시 데려와야지
First, I want to
thank you, Harry.
먼저 너한테 고맙다고
하고 싶구나, 해리
You must have shown me real
loyalty down in the Chamber.
넌 비밀의 방에서
날 향한 믿음을 보여 준 게 분명해
Nothing but that could
have called Fawkes to you.
그게 아니라면 퍽스는
네게 가지 않았을 거다
And...
그리고…
...second...
둘째로
...I sense that something
is troubling you.
뭔가 걱정되는 일이
있는 것 같은데
Am I right, Harry?
내 말이 맞느냐, 해리?
It's just...
그게…
You see, sir, I couldn't help but
notice certain things, certain...
우린 비슷한 점이 있다는 걸
부인할 수가 없어요
Certain similarities
between Tom Riddle and me.
톰 리들과
제 사이에 말이에요
I see.
그렇구나
Well, you can speak
Parseltongue, Harry. Why?
해리, 넌 뱀의 언어를
말할 수 있지, 왜일까?
Because Lord Voldemort
can speak Parseltongue.
그건 마왕 볼드모트가 뱀의 말을
할 수 있기 때문이란다
If I'm not mistaken, Harry...
내가 잘못 안 게 아니라면
...he transferred some
of his powers to you...
볼드모트가 네게
그 흉터를 줬던 날 밤
...the night he
gave you that scar.
그의 힘 일부가
네게 전해졌을 거다
Voldemort transferred
some of his powers to me?
볼드모트가 자기 힘을
제게 줬다고요?
Not intentionally...
일부러 그런 건 아니지만
...but yes.
그렇게 됐지
So the Sorting Hat was right.
I should be in Slytherin.
그럼 마법의 모자가 옳았네요
전 슬리데린에 들어가야 했어요
It's true. You possess many of the
qualities that Voldemort himself prizes.
맞아, 볼드모트 자신이 귀하게
여기는 특성을 너도 많이 소유했지
Determination,
resourcefulness...
결단력, 융통성
...and if I may say so, a certain
disregard for the rules.
그리고 또 규칙을
무시하는 버릇도 말이다
Why, then, did the Sorting
Hat place you in Gryffindor?
그럼 왜 마법의 모자가
너를 그리핀도르에 넣었을까?
- Because I asked it to.
- Exactly, Harry. Exactly.
- 제가 부탁했거든요
- 바로 그거야, 해리
Which makes you different
from Voldemort.
그래서 네가
볼드모트와 다른 거야
It is not our abilities that
show what we truly are.
우리의 진정한 모습을
보여 주는 건 우리의 능력이 아니라
It is our choices.
우리의 선택이란다
If you want proof why you
belong in Gryffindor...
네가 그리핀도르에
속해 있다는 증명을 원한다면
...then I suggest you look
more closely at this.
이걸 더 자세히 보거라
Be careful.
조심하렴
Godric Gryffindor.
고드릭 그리핀도르
It would take a true Gryffindor
to pull that out of the hat.
진정한 그리핀도르만이
그걸 모자에서 꺼낼 수 있다
Dobby.
도비
So this is your master. The
family you serve is the Malfoys.
그럼 네 주인은
말포이 가문이었구나
I'll deal with you later.
넌 나중에 벌을 주마
Out of my way, Potter.
비켜라, 포터
So it's true. You have returned.
정말 돌아오셨군요
When the governors learned that
Arthur Weasley's daughter...
이사회가 아서 위즐리의 딸이
비밀의 방에
...was taken into the Chamber,
they saw fit to summon me back.
잡혀간 걸 알자 나를 다시
불러야 한다고 결정했소
- Ridiculous. - Curiously,
Lucius, several of them...
- 말도 안 돼!
- 이상하게도 이사 몇 명은
...were under the impression that
you would curse their family...
나를 정직시키는 데
동의하지 않으면 당신이
...if they did not agree to
suspend me in the first place.
자기 가족들을
저주할 거라고 생각한 것 같소
- How dare you!
- Beg your pardon?
- 어떻게 그런 말을!
- 뭐라고요?
My sole concern has always
been and will always be...
늘 그랬지만 앞으로도
제 유일한 관심사는
...the welfare of this school...
이 학교의 안녕입니다
...and, of course, its students.
그리고 물론
학생들의 안전이죠
The culprit has been
identified, I presume?
그럼 범인은 밝혀졌겠군요?
Yes.
그럼요
And?
그래서…
Who was it?
누구였습니까?
Voldemort.
볼드모트였소
Only this time he chose to
act through somebody else...
다만 이번엔 다른 사람을 통해
행동하기로 했던 겁니다
...by means of this.
이걸 사용해서 말이오
I see.
그렇군요
Fortunately, our young
Mr. Potter discovered it.
다행히도 포터 군이
이걸 발견했소
One hopes that no more of Lord
Voldemort's old school-things...
앞으로는 볼드모트가
옛날 학생 시절 쓰던 물건이
...should find their way
into innocent hands.
순진한 사람의 손에
들어가지 않았으면 하오
The consequences for the one
responsible would be...
이 일에 대한
책임이 있는 사람은
...severe.
엄중히 다스려질 거요
Well, let us hope...
항상 포터 군이
가까이 있어서
...that Mr. Potter will always
be around to save the day.
우리를 구해 주기를
바래야겠군요
Don't worry. I will be.
걱정 마세요
그럴 거니까요
Dumbledore.
덤블도어 교수님
Come, Dobby. We're leaving.
도비, 이만 가자
Sir? I wonder if I
could have that?
교수님
제가 이걸 가져도 될까요?
Mr. Malfoy.
말포이 씨!
Mr. Malfoy!
I have something of yours.
당신 물건을 갖고 있어요
Mine? I don't know what
you're talking about.
내 거라고?
무슨 말인지 모르겠구나
I think you do, sir.
아실 텐데요
I think you slipped the diary
into Ginny Weasley's cauldron...
당신이 지니의 냄비에
그 일기장을 몰래 넣었잖아요
...that day at Diagon Alley.
그날, 다이애건 앨리에서요
You do, do you?
그렇게 생각하나?
Why don't you prove it?
어디 증명해 보지그래?
Come, Dobby.
가자, 도비
Open it.
열어 봐
Dobby.
도비
Master has given Dobby a sock.
주인님이 도비에게
양말 한 짝을 주셨어요
What? I didn't give...
뭐? 내가 언제…
Master has presented
Dobby with clothes.
주인님이 도비에게
옷을 선물해 주셨어요
Dobby is free.
도비는 자유예요
You lost me my servant!
내 하인을 잃게 하다니!
You shall not harm Harry Potter.
해리 포터를 해치게
놔두진 않아요!
Your parents were
meddlesome fools too.
네 부모도 참견하기 좋아하는
바보들이었지
Mark my words, Potter.
One day soon...
잘 들어라, 포터
조만간 너도
...you are going to meet
the same sticky end.
그들과 똑같은 비참한 결말을
맞게 될 거다
Harry Potter freed Dobby. How
can Dobby ever repay him?
해리 포터가 도비를 풀어 줬어요
이 은혜를 어떻게 갚죠?
- Just promise me something.
- Anything, sir.
- 하나만 약속해 줘
- 뭐든 말씀하세요
Never try to save my life again.
다시는 날 구해 주려고
하지 마
- Welcome back, Sir Nicholas.
- Thank you.
- 어서 오세요, 니콜라스 경
- 고맙다
- Good evening, Sir Nicholas.
- Good evening.
- 안녕하세요, 니콜라스 경
- 잘 있었니?
- Good to see you, Sir
Nicholas. - Thank you.
- 반가워요, 니콜라스 경
- 나도 반갑다
Hello.
안녕!
- Hermione! Welcome back.
- Thanks, Sir Nicholas.
- 헤르미온느, 잘 돌아왔다!
- 감사합니다
Harry. It's Hermione.
해리, 헤르미온느야!
- Welcome back, Hermione.
- It's good to be back.
- 잘 왔어, 헤르미온느
- 돌아오니 좋다
Congratulations. I can't
believe you solved it.
축하해! 너희들이
해결할 줄은 몰랐어
We had loads of help from you.
네 도움이 컸어
- We couldn't have done
it without you. - Thanks.
- 네가 없었으면 못 했을 거야
- 고마워
Could I have your
attention, please?
주목해 주세요
Before we begin the feast...
만찬을 시작하기 전에
...let us have a round of applause for
Professor Sprout, Madam Pomfrey...
스프라우트 교수님과
폼프리 부인에게 박수를 보냅시다
...whose Mandrake juice has been
so successfully administered...
두 분이 만든 맨드레이크 약 덕분에
마비된 사람들이
...to all who had
been Petrified.
모두 성공적으로 회복됐습니다
Also, in light of the
recent events...
그리고 이번에 일어난
사건을 볼 때
...as a school treat...
학교가 주는
선물의 의미로
...all exams have been canceled.
모든 시험을
취소하도록 하겠습니다
Oh, no.
안돼…
Sorry I'm late.
늦어서 미안해요
The owl that delivered my release
papers got all lost and confused.
내 석방 명령서를 배달한 부엉이가
길을 잃고 헤매는 바람에요
Some ruddy bird called Errol.
멍청한 새던데
이름이 에롤이라던가
And I'd just like to say that if it
hadn't been for you, Harry and Ron...
그리고 해리, 론
너희들이 아니었다면…
...and Hermione, of course...
물론 헤르미온느도 마찬가지고
...I would still be
you-know-where...
난 여전히
그 끔찍한 곳에 있었을 거야
...so I'd just like
to say thanks.
그래서 모두에게
감사하고 싶다
There's no Hogwarts
without you, Hagrid.
해그리드 아저씨가 없으면
호그와트도 없잖아요